善恶魔法学院
很久以前 两个法力高强的兄弟建立了一所学校
以保持童话世界中的善恶平衡
兄弟俩永远和平共处 分享权力
但世事往往变幻莫测
你作弊了
You cheated, you know.
决斗竞技场清楚地规定了不能用魔法
The Duel Arena has very clear rules. No magic.
赢了就不是作弊 被抓到才算
It's not cheating if you win. It's only cheating if you get caught.
-再来一轮？ -不 我们没时间了
-Shall we go another round? -No, we don't have time.
跟你训练是我每天唯一的享受
Sparring with you is the only part of the day I enjoy anymore.
我也很喜欢 但有人需要我们
I enjoy it too, but we're needed.
负责管理史上最重要的学校 难免会遇到一些麻烦
It's one of the downsides of overseeing the most important school ever built.
我厌倦了
And I'm bored.
拉法尔 你想怎么样？
Rafal, what do you want?
再来一局
Just one more round.
我们都用魔法
We'll both use our magic.
尽情发挥
No holds barred.
来吧 莱恩
Come on, Rhian.
让我看看该怎么打架
-Show me how it's done.
你就是停不下来…
You just don't stop--
拉法尔 够了！
Rafal, that's enough!
对你来说是吧 但一半已经满足不了我了
Maybe for you, but I'm done settling for half.
我全都要！
I want it all!
不要！
No!
拉法尔 你做了什么？那是…
Rafal, what have you done? That's…
血魔法
Blood magic.
我找了好几年 昨晚终于找到了
I've been searching for years, but last night, I finally found it.
拉法尔 这被禁是有原因的
Rafal, it's forbidden for a reason.
它会吞噬你 你无法控制它
It'll consume you. You can't control it.
我喜欢混乱
I prefer chaos.
几千年来 你总是让英雄占上风
Thousands of years, you always gave the heroes the upper hand!
我为了你保持平衡
I held the balance with you.
现在轮到我了
It's my turn now.
拉法尔…
Rafal…
规矩由我定
I dictate the terms.
这将会是一个截然不同的世界
And it's going to be a very different world.
我们可以合作
We can work together.
恶不合作
Evil doesn't cooperate.
恶不分享
Evil doesn't share.
待我功成
When I'm done…
恶不会输
…Evil won't lose.
不要啊！
No!
原谅我
Oh, Rafal.
多年后
在遥远的土地上
新的故事正在展开…
很久很久以前 有个叫索菲的女孩
Once upon a time, there lived a girl named Sophie.
是一位兼具极致美貌与优雅的勇者
A brave creature of exquisite beauty and uncommon grace…
她注定会改变世界
…who was destined to change the world.
听好了 最后说一次
Now, listen up for the last time,
你这懒惰荒唐的女孩
you lazy, ridiculous girl.
快从床上给滚我下来
Get your candied ass out of bed now!
索菲 我知道你能听见
Sophie, I know you can hear me!
救救我
-Someone save me.
好了 我醒了 别砸门了
Okay, I'm awake. Don't break the door down.
要是你五分钟内还没出来我就砸
I will, if you're not out in five minutes.
不要花一小时梳头发
-And no spending an hour on your hair.
至少我有头发
At least I have hair.
好了 冷静点 孩子们
All right, settle down, now, boys.
早上好 我亲爱的家人
Good morning, my dear family.
别浪费那个番茄 索菲 那个应该放进炖锅的
Hey, don't waste that tomato, Sophie! It was supposed to go in the stew!
开玩笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
与此同时 在加瓦尔登的另一边
Meanwhile, on the other side of Gavaldon,
城外 格雷夫斯山顶简朴的农舍
just outside of town, in a humble cottage on top of Graves Hill…
住着一位名叫阿加莎的女孩
…there lived a girl named Agatha.
妈的
Dang it.
你太擅长盯人比赛了 收割者
You're too good at staring contests, Reaper.
你能过来一下吗 阿吉？
-Come here a minute, Aggie?
我在给寡妇格伦菲制作太奶奶的爱情药水
I'm making Great-Grandma's love potion for the widow Grunfeld.
需要点东西
It needs something.
-毒堇 -当然了
-Hemlock. -Of course.
阿加莎不确定她妈妈到底是不是女巫
Agatha had no idea if her mother was actually a witch
因为她的药水从来没用
since her potions never worked.
但妈妈对阿加莎寄予了很高的希望
But it was in Agatha that her mother placed her highest hopes,
她知道女儿有做女巫的潜质
knowing that her daughter had the makings of a real witch.
阿加莎的伙伴们也有同感
-A sentiment shared by Agatha's peers.
女巫！
-Witch! Witch! Witch!
-烧死她！ -女巫！
-Burn her! Burn her! -Witch! Witch!
你们好 森林里的小朋友们
Hello there, my little forest friends.
-怪胎！ -变态！
-Weirdos! -Freaks!
-天啊 我恨这个小镇 -天啊 我恨这个小镇
God, I hate this town.
幸运的是 她们互相帮助
Fortunately, they had each other.
两个如此不同的女孩之间
A friendship between two such different girls
似乎不太可能产生友谊
might have seemed unlikely,
但她们从小就…
but theirs was a special bond…
恶心！
Oh, gross!
结下了很深的渊源
…forged at an early age.
是最爱索菲的母亲的死…
For it was the death of Sophie's mother, the person who loved her most…
永远记得你有多特别
Always remember how special you are.
你总有一天会改变世界
You're gonna change the world someday.
你会幸福地度过一生
Then you'll live happily ever after.
…给她带来一个更爱她的朋友
…that brought her a friend who loved her even more.
-是谁？ -这是我给你做的
-Who's there? -I… I made this for you.
你妈妈的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your mom.
在村里许愿树下
And it was beneath the village wishing tree
她们结下了一生的友谊
that they sealed a bond they knew would last a lifetime.
说了100次了 不行
Like, for literally the hundredth time, no.
不用做全套的美容
-It wouldn't have to be a whole makeover.
可以做个黄瓜眼膜 给你的毛孔做个磨砂
We could just do a cucumber eye mask. Maybe a pumice scrub for your pores.
嘿 丑鬼
-Hey, ugly.
你不回答吗？
Aren't you gonna answer him?
不是她 是你
Not her, you.
埃里克说你对他施了咒
-Oh. -Eric says you put a hex on him.
-埃里克是谁？ -我不知道
-Who's Eric?
-我们同班八年了 -他说你看他的眼神怪怪的
-We've been in the same class eight years. -He says you looked at him weird.
现在他感觉很痒
And now he's feeling all itchy.
对不起 这听起来像是卫生问题
I'm sorry, that sounds more like a hygiene issue.
说真的 是跳蚤吗？
Seriously. Lice, anyone?
闭嘴！
-Hey, shut up!
你们俩以为自己比我们强 但你们只是猪猡
You two think you're better than us, but really, you're just a prig and a pig.
怪胎
Freaks.
我是埃里克
And I'm Eric.
我觉得他喜欢你
You know, I think he likes you.
谁 埃里克？
Who, Eric?
不好意思 我们班有埃里克？
I'm sorry, there's an Eric?
我得从费雪太太那儿买点毒堇给我妈
Oh, I… I need to pick up some hemlock from Mrs. Fisher for my mom.
我也得买点绿色流苏
I gotta get some green fringe anyway.
-我在多维尔等你 -等等 索菲 我…
-I'll meet you at Deauville's. -Wait, no, Sophie, I…
好吧
Okay. Uh…
没事
Cool.
女巫
Witch.
她是个女巫
-She's a witch.
嗨
Hi.
你好啊 小家伙
Hello there, little guy.
你喜欢吗？
-Aw, yeah, you like that?
你是那个住在墓地的女孩
You're the girl lives in the graveyard.
我们住在墓地旁边
We live by the graveyard, yeah.
每个人都说你是女巫
You know, everyone… …and I mean everyone… says you're a witch.
你知道我们加瓦尔登以前会怎么对女巫吗？
You know what we used to do… what we used to do to witches in Gavaldon?
烧死她们
We burned 'em.
祝你今天愉快 兄弟
-You have a really nice day, buddy. -Whoa!
我们这儿不需要女巫
We don't want witches in this town.
你听到了吗？
Do you hear me?
这对加瓦尔登正派人来说是个威胁
It's a threat to the decent people of Gavaldon.
我真怀疑加瓦尔登有没有正派人
You know, I seriously doubt there are any decent people in Gavaldon.
-你没事吧？ -我没事
-You okay? -Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
我们走吧
Let's… Let's get out of here.
嘿 我们去多维尔看看她有没有新货
Hey, let's drop by Deauville's, see if she's got anything new.
你不用回家吗？
Oh, don't you have to get home, though?
■
多维尔故事书店
去看看她有没有什么好东西
C'mon. Let's see if she's got something good.
我最喜欢的读者！
My favorite readers.
还好你们来了
Good thing you stopped by.
昨天进了一大批货
We had a big delivery yesterday.
-有鬼故事吗？ -有几本有意思的
-Any ghost stories? -Yes, a few interesting-looking ones.
有新的童话故事吗？
Any new fairy tales?
都是你已经读得滚瓜烂熟的 索菲
Nothing you haven't read a thousand times before, Sophie.
但我看到有几本有趣的旧版
But I did spot some very interesting older editions in there.
看看吧！
Look, look! Dig around.
这可能听起来很疯狂
Okay, this might sound crazy,
但你有没有想过走出舒适区？
but you ever think about branching out of your comfort zone?
不要再读小孩子的书了？
Maybe, like, stop reading little kids' books? Aww.
读《荷姆克魯斯之血》？
To The Blood of the Homunculus?
不用了 谢谢
I'm good, thanks.
我就是想读《灰姑娘》
Give me Cinderella any day.
看看这里面的裙子
Just look at the dresses in here.
你找到了
You found it.
看看这印花
Just look at the embossing.
SGE是谁？
Who's S.G.E.?
不是谁 是善恶魔法学院
Not who, what. The School for Good and Evil.
你没听说过吗？
Don't tell me you've never heard of it.
-在哪里？ -没人知道
-Where is it? -No one knows.
另一个时代 另一个世界
Another time, another world.
但传说
But legend has it,
那里是每个伟大童话故事的起源地
it's where the true story behind every great fairy tale begins.
善院培养英雄
-Ooh. -The School for Good trains the heroes.
恶院培养恶人
The School for Evil, the villains.
-他们是这么说的 -疯人院里的人
-Or so they say. -The people in insane asylums, you mean.
不好说哦
I wouldn't be so sure of that.
20年前 一个名叫利奥诺拉的女孩在血红的天色下
Twenty years ago, a girl named Leonora was taken from our village
从我们村庄被带走
-under a blood-red sky.
很多人认为 学校想要她是有原因的
Many believe the school wanted her for some reason.
她怎么了？
-What happened to her?
没人知道
-No one knows.
从此杳无音讯
She was never heard from again.
那也算离开这里的一个途径吧 他们接受新生吗？
That'd be one way to get out of this town. Do they ever accept new students?
你开玩笑吧？
You're joking, right?
对
Yeah.
“亲爱的善恶学院
Dear School for Good and Evil.
作为未来的公主 我非常渴望加入贵校
As a future princess, I wish very much to attend your esteemed institution.
请容我列出我作为独一无二合格候选人的特质
Allow me to list the many attributes that I believe make me a uniquely qualified candidate.
我从小就知道
From a very young age,
我的宿命就是改变世界”
I've always known it's been my destiny to change the world.
为了逃离她现在生活…
Willing to try anything to escape her current life…
一定要是真的呀
Please be real.
…索菲把对未来的所有期许
…Sophie entrusted all her hopes for the future
寄托在许愿树的身上
to the powers of the Wishing Tree.
-我恨我继母！ -什么？
-Oh, I hate my stepmother! -Whoa, whoa. What?
工厂里有个空缺职位 她逼我去工作赚钱
There's an opening at the factory, so she's making me quit school to bring in more money.
那我也辍学 她能帮我找份工作和你一起吗？
So I will quit too. Can she get me a job there with you?
然后呢？
And then what?
淹没在这个小镇的人海之中？
We just fade into this town like everyone else?
阿吉 我妈妈说过 我是要做大事的
No, Aggie. My mom said I'm supposed to do something important.
重要的事
Something that matters.
所以我今晚就走
So, I'm leaving tonight.
等等 索菲 你从来没离开过加瓦尔登
Wait, Sophie… you've never even set foot outside Gavaldon.
你根本不知道外面有什么 我们都不知道
You don't even know what's out there. None of us really do.
所以才要走
That's the point.
你知道 如果我被困在这里 什么都不会发生
You know nothing can ever happen for me as long as I'm stuck here.
我不甘心过平凡的生活
I can't settle for an ordinary life.
我不会的
I won't.
看
Hey, look.
记得吗？
Remember?
嗯 我上周在阁楼里找到的
Yeah, I found it in my attic last week.
看见没？你已经做了一件重要的事
See? You already did do something that matters.
你成为了我朋友
The day you became my friend.
拜托 没有你我受不了这地方的
Please, I can't handle this place without you.
我会跟你爸妈谈谈 告诉他们这有多不公平
I'll talk to your mom and dad, and I'll tell them how unfair this is.
我会称你为 加瓦尔登女王索菲
I'll call you Queen Sophie of Gavaldon.
我甚至可以让你给我化妆
I will even let you give me a makeover.
拜托你别走
Just please don't go.
-好 -你保证？
-Okay. -You promise?
我保证
I promise.
谢谢！
-Oh, thank you! -Oh!
“加瓦尔登女王索菲”
"Queen Sophie of Gavaldon."
就是在那一刻 索菲决定
It was at that moment Sophie decided
她不能幻想自己的人生将会魔法般改变
she was beyond wishing for her life to magically improve.
是时候掌控自己的命运了
It was time to take charge of her destiny.
即使这意味着要违背她对她唯一的好朋友的承诺
Even if it meant breaking the promise she'd made to her best and only friend.
非常抱歉 阿吉
I'm so sorry, Aggie.
但有些愿望太强大了 无法收回
But some wishes are simply too powerful to take back.
离开加瓦尔登
-你还是准备逃走 -阿吉 对不起
-You were gonna run away after all? -Aggie, I'm sorry.
那是什么？
What was that?
血红的天空
The red sky.
要来了
It's happening.
索菲
Sophie.
嘿 我们得离开这里
Hey, we have to get out of here.
-阿吉 这是我的愿望 -什么？
-Aggie, this is what I wished for. -You what?
索菲！
Sophie!
坚持住！
Hold on!
我来了！
I'm coming!
再见 加瓦尔登！
So long, Gavaldon!
永别了 庸庸碌碌！
Farewell, mediocrity!
再见了 不思进取！
-Goodbye, low ambition!
阿吉 不要！
-Aggie, no!
请让我走！
Please let me go!
不可能！我绝对不会放你走！
No way! I'm never letting you go!
不
-No.
阿吉 这是一件好事
No, Aggie, what was happening was a good thing.
对不起 索菲 我不能冒那个险
I'm sorry, Sophie, but I… I couldn't take that chance.
我不能让你出事
I can't let anything bad happen to you.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我的天
Oh my God! Oh my God! Oh my God!
阿吉 太好了
Aggie, this is good.
不 这不好！
No, no, no, no! This is not good!
没事
It's okay!
就是这样 这是真的 我没说错
This is it! This is real! I was right!
阿吉 你看 那一定是善院
Aggie, look. That must be the School for Good.
太美了
It's so beautiful.
等等 那就是…
Wait, that means that's--
天呐 另一个
Oh God, the other one.
阿吉 这就是我想要的一切
Aggie, this is everything I've ever wanted.
这不是我想要的
This is not what I wanted!
索菲 我们得回去了 你知道我妈妈离不开我
No, Sophie, we have to get back. You know my mom can't get by without me.
它把我放在善院后就会带你回家的
I'm sure this will take you home once it drops me at the Good school.
把我俩都带回去！
I want it to take us both back!
不是吧 阿吉！
Oh, Aggie!
不！你应该把我送去善院 不是她！
No! You're supposed to drop me at the Good school, not her!
不 带我回去 求你了！
No, take me back! Please!
不！你不明白！我是好…
No! You don't understand! I'm Good--
这下可好 那鸟吃了我的上衣
Ah, great. The bird ate my shirt.
哇
Oh wow.
我能摸摸你的头发吗？
Can I touch your hair?
大多数女巫没有公主一样的头发
-Most witches don't have princess hair.
肯定闻起来像蛋糕
-I bet it smells like cake.
我喜欢蛋糕
I love cake.
-我不是女巫！ -喂 你要去哪里？
-I'm not a witch! -Hey! Hey, where are you going?
拜托！
Oh, come on!
救救我！
-Help me!
排队 新人
Fall in line, newbie.
-对不起！ -小心点 怪胎
-Sorry. -Watch it, freak.
嘿 不！
Hey, no!
你听我说 我不应该在这里 我是好人！
You have to listen to me. I am not supposed to be here. I'm Good!
天啊 我讨厌开学日
God, I hate move-in day.
我应该是公主 不是恶人！
I'm supposed to be a princess, not a villain!
不要啊！
No!
她刚刚杀了个仙子吗？
Did she just kill a fairy?
什么？
Uh, what?
天啊
-Son of a-- -Oh dear.
你一定是迷路了
You must be lost.
何止是迷路了
Yeah. Yeah, that is an understatement.
我要怎么出去？
-How do I get out of here? I…
那到底是什么？
Ugh. What the hell is it?
看起来像个女巫
It looks like a witch.
我觉得是巨怪
I'm thinking a troll.
我觉得是恶魔
I say demon.
也许是半驼背
Maybe part hunchback?
我没有驼背
I don't have a hunch.
那你真的需要个裁缝
Then you really need a tailor.
我要怎么去那所学校？
How do I get over to that school?
我闻闻就知道
I knew from its smell.
是个无望
It's a Never.
听着 我需要找到我的朋友
Just listen! I just need to find my friend.
算了 仙子会处理她的
Ah, whatever, the fairies will get rid of her.
来吧 姑娘们
-Come, girls.
什么？我走了
-Mm. -What? I'm leaving.
不 我得…
No, no, no. I need--
别这样！
-Stop doing that!
你在…
What are you…?
不 放开我！
No, let me go!
放开我！
Get off of me!
又是我 握个手
Me again. Put her there.
比我自己的手还干净 相信我
It's cleaner than my own hand. Trust me.
-对了 我是霍特 -霍特？
-I'm Hort, by the way. -Hort?
听起来像是呕吐物的名字
That sounds like something you cough up.
这是我听过最好的话了
That's the nicest thing anyone's ever said to me.
怪人
Weirdo.
不好意思 女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
你似乎是负责人 我走错学校了
You seem to be in charge, and I am in the wrong school.
好痛苦 根本不可能
Ooh! How distressful. And improbable.
退后 你叫什么？
-Back up. Your name?
不如我来猜猜看
Actually, you know what? I wanna guess it.
你不会知道的
You won't know it.
索菲
Mm, Sophie.
加瓦尔登来的
Of Gavaldon.
我猜对了吗？
Did I guess it?
-我总能猜对 -肯定是搞错了
-I always do. -There must be a mistake.
-我显然… -你是读者？
-I clear-- -You're the Reader.
我会读书 如果你是这个意思
-I read, if that's what you mean. -Shh, shh, shh. It's not.
不是 每隔一段时间都会有一个幸运儿从外界
Every so often, a very lucky candidate from the outside
被选入这个神圣的机构
is selected for admission to this hallowed institution.
我们称他们为读者
We call them… Readers
因为他们只能读到这里起源的神奇的历险
because they only get to read about the amazing adventures that originate here.
失陪了
-Now, please, excuse me.
我要照顾新入校的恶人了
I have fresh villainy to attend to.
表演时间到
Showtime!
注意！
-Attention!
注意 未来的恶人！
-Attention, future Evil!
只要睁开眼睛你们小小的充血的眼睛
If you open your tiny little bloodshot eyes,
就会在大厅里找到宿舍分配和课程表
you'll find your dormitory and class schedules around the hall.
两者都背下来就好了
It would serve you well to memorize both.
让我为你们感到骄傲
Make me proud.
我的天啊
Oh my God.
别再碰我了
Don't you ever touch me again.
好吧！
-All right! Okay.
我还以为仙子都是客客气气的
I thought fairies were supposed to be nice.
♪ 为他的名增添荣耀 ♪
♪ Bring honor to his name ♪
我一定在地狱里
Oh, I must be in hell.
这真是地狱
Well, this is hell, all right.
什么…
What…?
-妈呀… -你好呀
-Holy sh-- -Well, hello.
看来你找到梳妆室了
I see you found the Groom Room.
做得好 加瓦尔登的阿加莎
Well done, Agatha of Gavaldon.
我能建议你在入学前梳洗一下吗？
Might I suggest you clean up a bit before orientation?
好好梳洗一下
Or perhaps clean up a lot.
你怎么知道我的名字？
How do you know my name?
因为我在等着你的到来
Because I've been expecting you.
我是多维教授
I am Professor Dovey,
为你提供各种帮助
here to help however I can.
终于有人来帮忙了 我朋友索菲想来这里
Finally. My friend Sophie wanted to be here.
-无望？没有 -什么？
-The Never? No. -The what?
你朋友是无望
Your friend is a Never.
你是永远
You are an Ever.
永远 因为我们相信永远幸福
Ever, because we believe in living happily ever after.
无望 因为他们不相信
Nevers, because they don't.
恶院 善院
School for Evil, School for Good.
-邪恶… -我懂了
-Evil-- -Yup, okay, I got it.
但显然有一个严重的错误
But clearly, there's been a mistake.
看看我
I mean, look at me.
亲爱的
My dear,
人有多善良不只是根据外表断定的
one doesn't measure one's goodness just by how one looks.
是根据你的行为
-No, it's about what one does.
如果你在这里 你一定有强大的能力
If you're here, you must have great… power.
相信我 我没有
Trust me, I don't.
那你需要学会召唤力量
Well then, I bet you just need to learn to summon it.
感受一下 因为情感会带来魔法
Feel it. Because magic follows emotion.
情感越强烈 魔力就越强
The stronger the emotion, the more powerful the magic.
激起足够的热情
-Summon enough passion,
你将无所不能
and you can accomplish anything.
给你的
For you.
-你怎么做到的？ -我跟你说了
-How did you do that? -I just told you.
-好吧 -对
-Okay. -Yes.
谢谢你的表演
Thank you so much for the show.
你变你的魔术 女士
Um, have fun with your magic tricks, lady.
我得找到我的朋友 回到加瓦尔登
I've gotta find my friend and get back to Gavaldon.
停下！
Stop!
听着 如果真的有错
Look, if there was a mistake,
有人就会被炒
then it is one that someone is going to get fired for.
字面意义的
-Literally.
所以在我们解决这件事之前假装没有错误 好吗？
So, let's pretend there is not a mistake until we can sort this all out, yes?
再说了 没有回去的路
Besides, there is no way back.
等等 什么？
Wait, what?
我知道！穿上你的盔甲吧
Oh, I know! Let's get you in your armor.
对
-Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
看看！
-Oh, yes! Look at them!
让我猜猜 你不喜欢粉色？
Let me guess. You're not a pink person?
没问题！
Not a problem!
我们还有玫瑰、紫红、脸红
We also have rose, fuchsia, blush,
西瓜、芙蓉
watermelon, hibiscus.
这么多颜色！
So many colors!
我爱我的工作
-I just love my job.
-索菲！ -阿吉！
-Wait, Sophie! -Aggie!
-嘿！ -嘿！
-Hey! -Hey!
他们让你穿礼服？
They gave you a gown?
坐下 把嘴闭上 读者！
-Sit down and shut up, Reader!
-等等！ -来吧
-Wait. -Come on.
好！
Okay.
待在那里！
And stay there!
嘿
Hey.
又是我
Me again.
我的天
Oh my God.
我父亲让我不要跟读者说话 说他们会带来厄运
My father tells me not to talk to Readers. He says they're bad luck.
你可能读过我爸的故事 虎克船长
You've probably read about my father. Captain Hook?
他有艘很厉害的船
He's got a pretty awesome ship.
你想咬一口吗？又好又臭
-Do you want a bite? It's nice and putrid.
优雅美丽先请
Grace and beauty first?
-如果你坚持的话 克拉丽莎 -很高兴你也同意
-Oh, if you insist, Clarissa. -So glad you agree.
欢迎 一年级新生！
-Welcome, first-year students!
我是多维教授
I am Professor Dovey,
善校院长
Dean of the School for Good.
永远！
Evers! Evers! Evers! Evers! Evers!
我是莱索女士 恶校院长
And I'm Lady Lesso, Dean of the School for Evil.
杀了你们！
Kill you! Kill you! Kill you! Kill you! Kill you!
-善院没有男生吗？ -有很多
-There's no boys in the School for Good? -Ugh, there's plenty.
准备好被恶心到吧
And get ready to be nauseous.
按照传统
As per tradition,
去年胜出的学校…
the winning school from last year…
又是我们 想不到吧
Us again. Imagine that!
-想象 -…将展示他们 的
-Hmm. Imagine. -…will now grace us all
骑士风范
with a display of their chivalrous talents.
先生们！
-Ugh. -Gentlemen!
一群弱鸡
What a bunch of losers.
天啊
Oh my.
是不是很棒？
-Aren't they wonderful?
如果各位的舞跳完了
If you boys are finished with dance class, maybe you'd like to have a real fight.
-也许就准备好真正的战斗了吧 -哦不
Oh no.
怎么样？
What do you say?
那是谁？
-Who… is… that?
是泰德罗斯！
It's Tedros!
他爸是国王
His dad was king,
当然他要单独入场
so of course he has to have his own stupid entrance.
♪ You are the sun ♪
♪ You are the only one… ♪
知道吗？速战速决
You know what? Let's make it easy for you.
冲啊！
Charge!
♪ Be my ♪
-♪ Be my ♪
♪ Be my little rock and roll queen ♪
好！
Yes!
-♪ Be my, be my… ♪
我不知道拥有个圆桌有什么大不了的
I don't know what the big deal about owning a round table is, anyway.
他父亲是亚瑟王？
His father was King Arthur?
无聊
Yawn.
哇
Wow.
-♪ Be my ♪
♪ Be my ♪
他...
He…
干得好 伙计们
-Nice work, fellas.
让我们看看你真正战斗时的样子 小白脸
Let's see how you do in a real fight, pretty boy.
准备去死吧
Prepare to die.
打他！
Get him! Get him!
拜托
Oh, come on.
既然要打 就好好干一场
If we're gonna do this, we might as well do it right.
拜托！犯规！
Oh, come on! Foul!
任何人都能…他都有魔剑
Anybody! He's got a magical sword.
这公平吗？
How's that fair?
那是神剑
That's Excalibur.
真的吗？
Really?
我知道 我多邪恶
I know. How evil of me.
妈的
Dammit.
你们又输了 多好
Oh, how good of you to lose again.
太棒了！
Bravo! Bravo!
英勇的展示！
-A heroic display!
看…
Look--
-不好意思 小姐 我相信… -我不属于这里？我知道
-Excuse me, milady. I believe, uh-- -That I don't belong here? Yeah, I know.
反正也不想要你傻气的玫瑰
Don't want your stupid rose anyway.
顺便说一句 这是普通女孩的样子
Oh, and by the way, this is what a normal girl looks like.
他是想给我的
He intended it for me.
普通女孩
Normal girl.
我旁边有个空位 泰迪
There's an open seat next to me, Teddy.
顺便说一句 你不知道我要说什么
And, for the record, you don't know what I was about to say, but… nice try.
他是什么味道？
What did he smell like?
自负
Ego.
在这两所学校里
In these two schools,
我们会扫清困惑
we will take away any confusion
让你们的灵魂尽可能纯净
and make your souls as pure as possible.
纯粹善良
Pure Good.
或是纯粹邪恶
Or pure Evil.
未来的英雄和坏人
Future heroes and villains,
你们被选中
you have been chosen
保护并维系
to protect and maintain
善与恶之间的平衡
the balance between Good and Evil.
因为如果平衡被破坏了…
For if that balance is ever compromised--
这些话还不必对我们的新朋友说吧？
I don't think we need to get into that just now with our new friends, do we?
快乐的开学日
-It's such a happy first day.
别扫兴了
-Let's not be downers, hmm?
再说 我相信新一级学生会表现特别优越
Besides, I'm sure this new class will perform exceptionally well.
就像各位的父母一样
And like your parents before you,
你们来到这里是因为
you are all here because
故事世界需要伟大的英雄和反派
the world of story needs great heroes and villains
教会外面的人
to teach the people of the outside world
如何做出自己的选择
to make choices to find their way.
所以要遵守规则 认真学习
So, obey the rules, study hard, and remember,
记住 故事家只会选择最优秀的学生
the Storian only chooses the very best of our students
书写传奇
for their own adventure.
万一我们进错了学校怎么办？
But what if we've been dropped in the wrong school?
或是选错了人 我们必须马上回家？
Or there's been a mistake and we need to go home immediately?
善恶学院没有错误
There are no mistakes in the School for Good and Evil,
祝各位学期愉快
so… have a nice semester.
学生们 到你们的寝室报到
All students, report to your assigned sleeping quarters.
完美
-Perfect.
善者不容恶
The Good do not room with Evil.
丽娜 让仙子们把我的包拿来
Reena… Tell the fairies to come get my bags.
我要搬走
I'm moving.
我会很想你们的
Mm, but I'll miss you so.
尽量不要破坏任何东西
Try not to ruin anything.
祝你好梦 无望
Sweet dreams, Never.
喂！
Hey!
你们不明白 我得找到我的朋友！
No, no, no! No, you don't understand! I need to find my friend!
就说我们会抓到她的
Ugh, I told you we'd get her.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你叫贝儿 安娜塔西娅 还是糖梅？
It's Belle. Or Anastasia. Or Sugar Plum.
其实我叫索菲
-Actually, my name is Sophie.
你们两个真是没礼貌
You two have no manners.
欢迎来到66号房
Welcome to room 66.
我是点点 罗伯特德雷诺的女儿
I'm Dot, daughter of Robert de Rainault.
-罗伯特… -拜托？
-Robert… -Hello?
诺丁汉警长
The Sheriff of Nottingham.
没关系 他不是很有名
It's okay. He's not, like, super famous.
是啊 谁听说过罗宾汉呢？
Yeah, who's ever heard of Robin Hood?
好好修历史 小甜甜
-Learn your history, cream puff.
好了 这位是阿纳迪尔
Anyway, that's Anadil.
这一缕阳光是海丝特
-And that ray of sunshine is Hester.
你可以睡在我旁边 索菲
-You can bunk next to me, Sophie.
反派叫这名字真好笑
That's a funny name for a villain.
拜托
-Oh, please.
-她太不像反派了 -我当然不是
-She's so not a villain. -Of course I'm not.
看看我
Look at me.
我看起来像女巫
Do I look like a witch?
还是巨怪还是恶心的老巫婆？
Or a troll? Or some disgusting old hag?
那巫婆是我妈妈
That hag is my mother.
好 往上看 阿加莎
Okay, eyes up, Agatha.
只是丘比特 太笨了
It's just a Cupid, stupid.
好了 别怂
Okay, don't be lame.
别怂
Don't be lame.
你可以的
You got this.
好的
Okay.
嗨
Uh, hi.
学生不许上岩壁
Students aren't allowed on the ledge.
准备受罚吧
Prepare for punishment!
我还以为加瓦尔登就够糟了
-And I thought Gavaldon was bad.
好了 公主 有什么重要的事值得你一路爬到那里
All right, princess. What's so important we had to trek all the way up here?
我还穿着高跟鞋
I'm in heels, you know.
是读者
-It's the Readers.
他们坚定地认为自己不该在这儿
And their insistence that they shouldn't be where they are.
感觉有些不对劲
And something does feel wrong.
唯一不对劲的是 校长一开始就不该录取她们
The only thing that feels wrong is the School Master's decision to bring them here in the first place.
万一他弄错呢？
What if he did make a mistake?
如果他把她们分配进了错误的学校
What if he dropped them in the wrong schools
然后发生了可怕的事呢？
and something terrible happens?
他不会承认的
He'd never admit it.
为了脸面 他会怪罪于我们
He'd blame one of us to save face,
你知道会发生什么
and you know what would happen then.
没有错 再说了 我觉得你会开心的
There is no mistake. Besides, I'd think you'd be happy.
我又得到了一个资质平平的人
I'm stuck with yet another underachiever.
加瓦尔登的索菲
Sophie of Gavaldon.
什么？不 什么意思？
What? What? No. Whatever do you mean?
拜托 反派已经两百多年没赢过了
Pfft. Please. Evil hasn't won anything in over 200 years.
你们有几次差点就又赢了
Well, you've come close a couple of times.
差点没有用！
Close doesn't cut it!
我得让我的学生加倍努力
I just have to work my students twice as hard.
因为邪恶如果没有善良那么强大
Because a world where Evil is not as powerful as Good
世界就不平衡
is a world out of balance.
好 请允许我失陪
Now, if you'll excuse me…
我还有很多工作要做
…I have a lot of work to do.
莱索！
Lesso!
离索菲远点 巫婆
Stay away from Sophie, little witch.
她有使命要完成
-She has a destiny to fulfill.
她现在属于我了
And she belongs to me now.
你在哪里 索菲？
Where are you, Sophie?
我相信你妈妈的内心很美
I'm sure your mother's beautiful on the inside.
但我得去另一所学校 我是好人
-I have to get to the other school. I'm Good.
对 擅长隐藏你的邪恶
Yeah, at disguising your Evil.
我不邪恶！
I am not Evil.
我们用科学来解决吧
Let's settle this with science.
如果她是好人 掉下去的时候会有仙子接住
If she's Good, the fairies will catch her when she falls.
但如果她摔碎脑壳 死相惨不忍睹
But if she smashes on the rocks in a gruesome, skull-splintering death,
她就是邪恶的
she's Evil.
后者 我要看后者
The second one. Do the second one.
但她是个反派 她只是还不知道
But she is a villain. She just doesn't know it yet.
不 我是好人
No, I'm Good!
她像永远一样爱发牢骚
Aw, she whines like an Ever.
闻起来像永远
Smells like an Ever.
头发也像永远
-Has hair like an Ever.
曾经的头发
Or had.
喂！
Hey!
别碰我头发！
Not the hair!
你们想要我是好人的证据？ 照照镜子吧
You want proof that I'm Good? Then get a mirror, and look in it.
你这丑婆娘！
You hag!
说了 绝对是邪恶
Told ya. Definitely Evil.
索菲！
Sophie!
阿吉！
Aggie!
阿吉 嘿
-Aggie, hey.
-来吧 -等等 我们去哪里？
-Come on. -Wait, where are we going?
带你离开这里
To get you out of here.
-太好了 -不好
-Oh, good. -Not good.
有人想害你
Some… thing is after you.
我看到了
I saw it.
我们现在就要结束这一切
Okay. So we're ending this now.
阿吉 别！不值得！
Aggie, no! It's not worth it!
来吧
Come on.
阿加莎的计划很简单
Agatha's plan was simple.
找到校长
Find the School Master
向他申请离开学校
and plead their case to leave the school directly to him.
只有一个问题
There was only one problem.
我们怎么进去？
How do we get in?
他绝对上来这里了 我看到了
He definitely came up here. I saw it.
嘿！让我们进去！
Hey! Let us in!
很好
Great.
现在我们被困在这里了
Now we're stuck up here.
她们准备好见到暗中等待她们的东西了吗？
Would they be prepared for what awaited them in the shadows?
阿加莎在黑暗中呼唤
Agatha called into the darkness.
有人吗？
Hello?
但没有回应
-But there was no response.
那是谁？
Who is that?
索菲发现了墙上的书
Sophie discovered that books lined the walls,
写着来自世界各地的故事
filled with stories from every corner of the world.
你知道我们能听到你的旁白 怪胎
-You know we hear you narrating, weirdo.
如果你想吓我们 这可不管用
If you're trying to scare us, it's not working.
姑娘们听到了黑暗中的摩擦声
The girls heard a scratching in the blackness.
小心翼翼地朝那边移动
They moved warily toward it.
开玩笑吧
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
这都是一支愚蠢的笔说的？
-All of that, and it's a dumb pen?
索菲 住手！
Sophie, stop!
别碰！
-Don't touch!
从来没有学生进过我的塔
You know, no students have ever made it into my tower.
我就知道你们很特别
I knew you were special.
故事家在你们来到之前
The Storian began writing your story
就开始写故事了
before you even arrived.
所以我很困惑
Guess that's why I'm so confused
为何你们俩想离开
as to why the two of you want to leave.
她想离开 我不想
She wants to leave. I don't.
索菲 我得带你离开这里
Sophie, I have to get you out of here.
女士们 我向你们保证 你俩在这里很安全
Ahem. Ladies, ladies. I can assure you, you are both perfectly safe here.
我们以保护我们的读者为荣
We pride ourselves on protecting our Readers.
是吗？那我看到纠缠索菲的那团血 算怎么回事呢？
Really? Then what about the spinning tower of blood I just saw obsessing over Sophie?
好吧 你看
Well, my friend, you see,
好多随性的鬼魂和有针对性的咒语四处飘浮
there are so many random spirits and personalized spells flying around this school,
我跟不上
even I can't keep up.
我觉得她有危险
Well, I think she's in danger.
可惜了 我们不能在这里逐渐消沉
So, unfortunately, we can't just languish here
由着你们在傻气的童话故事里训练我们
while you train us to be in some silly fairy tales.
我们的毕业生活在改变世界的真实事件中
Our graduates live the very real events that change the world,
那些事会成为改变世界的故事
which become the stories that change the world.
你是想告诉我
You're trying to tell me that Snow White
白雪公主、灰姑娘和杰克与豌豆的故事是真的？
and Cinderella and Jack and the Beanstalk were real?
跟大力士
As were Hercules
还有辛巴达
and Sinbad
还有熙德一样
and El Cid
以及那些与邪恶势力对抗的人
and all the others who have battled the forces of Evil.
我们教你们如何达成使命
We teach you how to fulfill your destiny.
这正是我想学的 但你把我分进了错误的学校
And that's exactly what I wanna learn, but you put me in the wrong school.
我应该在善院
I'm supposed to be in Good.
你弄错了
You made a mistake.
先生
Sir.
也许我错了 但我需要你证明
Well, perhaps I have. But I'll need you to prove it.
为什么？这是你的错
Why, if it's your mistake?
因为故事家写的故事
Because once something is written by the Storian,
只有故事家能改变
only the Storian can change its course.
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
我们要怎么改变它的想法？ 都不知道它有没有脑子
How are we supposed to change its mind, if it even has one?
有的
Oh, but it does.
只有一个办法能够破解
And there's only one way, really.
什么是邪恶永远无法拥有
What is the one thing that Evil can never have
而善良却不可或缺的？
that Good can never do without?
我知道 礼貌
Oh, I know. Manners.
城堡
A castle.
秀发 马
Amazing hair. A horse.
真爱
True love.
通常是通过亲吻表现出来的
Which is traditionally manifested in a kiss.
所以你是说…
So you're saying…
真不敢相信我会这么说
I can't believe I'm actually saying this.
如果索菲吻到了她的真爱
If Sophie were to kiss her true love,
就能向作家证明你们错了？
that would prove to Quilly over there that you were wrong about us?
如果恶院的人赢得了真爱之吻
If one from School of Evil won true love's kiss,
会改变一切
it would change everything.
-我就可以留下来换学校？ -索菲！
-And I could stay and switch schools? -Sophie.
这是我一直想要的 阿吉 我不能回加瓦尔登
This is all I've ever wanted, Aggie. I can't go back to Gavaldon.
不能回到我以前的生活
Not to my old life.
我再也不会有这样的机会了
I will never get this chance again.
求求你 让我做吧
Please, let me do this.
我会考虑的
-I'll think about it. -Excellent.
很好
Well,
赶紧去找王子接吻吧
I guess somebody better go find herself a prince to kiss.
但记住 亲爱的读者
But remember, dear Reader,
吻都是有代价的
no kiss comes without its price.
什么意思？
-Wait, what does that mean?
各位早上好 起床咯！
Good morning, darlings! Rise and shine!
本学期第一个活动 永远舞会两周后就会举行
The first event of the semester, the Evers Ball, is only two weeks away,
你们还有很多要学习的
and you've got a lot to learn.
-早上好 -早上好
-Good morning. -Good morning.
早上好 阿加莎
Good morning, Agatha.
醒醒 卑鄙的人！
Wake up, despicables!
♪ Unrelentlessly upset ♪
♪ You say these are the golden years ♪
♪ But I wish I could disappear ♪
♪ Ego crush is so severe ♪
索菲的亲吻候选人
♪ God, it's brutal out here ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
那是谁？
Who's that?
-深色头发 -崔斯坦
-Dark… Dark hair. -Tristan.
我接到了他的玫瑰
I caught his rose.
我希望他邀我参加永远舞会
I hope he invites me to the Evers Ball.
必须有个男生邀请你 不然你就不及格了
You have to get a boy to ask you, or you fail.
千万不能不及格
And you do not want to fail.
三个不及格就被开除了
Three fails, and you're expelled.
他们会把我赶走？
-Wait, you mean they kick you out? -Uh…
不是
No.
他们会把你变成别的东西
They actually turn you into something else.
比如会说话的茶壶
Like a talking tea kettle
或是老鼠
or a mouse
甚至更糟
or something much worse.
永远变不回来？什么？
Wait, like forever? What?
变丑！
Uglify!
为什么我们要变丑？
-Why do we need to be ugly?
霍特！醒醒！
-Hort! Wake up!
因为这能让孩子哭
Oh, because it makes little children cry.
错
Wrong.
那只是锦上添花
-That's merely a bonus.
为什么要让人反感？
Why be revolting and repugnant?
也是我的问题
My question exactly.
不在乎你的外表
Ah, not caring how you look
逼迫你用自己的头脑
forces you to use your intelligence.
丑陋就是自由！
Ugliness is freedom!
我的牙掉了
My tooth just fell out.
太恶心了 我不在乎
It's disgusting. And I don't care.
丑化学
那就是力量！
And that is power!
丑化学
沉静下来 姑娘们
-Bring it down, girls.
我是阿尼蒙教授
-I am Professor Anemone,
我来向你们展示
and I am here to show you
如何通过美成为一个真正强大的女人
how to become a truly powerful woman through beauty.
淑女的微笑就是她的剑
A lady's smile is a sword
能赢得争夺真爱的战争
in the battle for life and for true love.
拿起镜子
-So, pick up your mirrors…
出击
…and strike!
-很好 丽娜 -谢谢 教授
-Lovely, Reena. -Thank you, Professor.
太美了 碧翠丝
Exquisite, Beatrix.
对不起 这感觉太不对了
I'm sorry. This just feels so wrong.
你要通过微笑赋予我们力量？
Smiling? That's how you're empowering us?
微笑是通过本科目的要求
Smiling is a strict requirement for passing this course.
所以 如果不想挂科 就展示你们的笑容
So, show me your smile if you don't want to fail.
我的笑容？
My… smile?
我感觉不安全
I don't feel safe.
等等 这是什么？
Wait. What is that?
挂科了 读者
A fail, Reader.
因为我微笑得不好 就让我挂科？
Wait, you're… you're failing me for being a bad smiler?
对
Yeah.
继续努力吧
Let's get to work.
好 一饮而尽
Ah, now, prepare to drink up
看看你们能有多丑、多有力量
and see how ugly and powerful you can be.
读者
-Reader.
你先来
You're first.
不 我不想变丑
No. I don't want to be ugly.
这不是我
-It's not who I am.
很快就是了 霍特！
Not yet. Hort!
是先生 曼利教授
Uh, yes, sir, Professor Manley.
很抱歉
Sorry about this.
但别担心 在我眼里你还是美的
But don't worry. You'll still look beautiful to me.
是阿加莎 对吧？
It's, um, Agatha, right?
-嗨 -你介意我跟你一起坐吗？
-Hi. -Do you mind if I sit with you?
-不介意 -太好了
-No. -Great.
你随意
-If you want to. -Uh…
我是格雷戈
I'm Gregor.
格雷戈尔·查铭
Um, Gregor Charming.
白马王子的儿子
The, uh… the prince's son.
我会尽量别太迷人
I'll try not to be too charming.
-我是阿加莎 -我听说你不想来这里
-I'm Agatha. -I heard you don't want to be here.
我也不想
Well, I don't either.
-你不想吗？ -我不适合当王子
-You don't? -I'm not cut out to be a prince.
我不是这样的
It's… It's not who I am.
你知道我宁愿做什么吗？ 开自己的杂货店
Do you know what I'd rather do? Run my own grocery store.
-真的吗？ -对
-Wait, really? -Yeah.
我喜欢吃东西 但我不卖肉 因为我见不得血
I love food, but I wouldn't sell meat 'cause I can't stand the sight of blood.
所以我今天挂科了 在决斗中被划到了
That's actually why I got a fail today. I got nicked in a duel.
不好意思 他们因为一个伤口让你挂科？
I'm sorry, they failed you for one tiny cut?
不仅如此
Not quite.
我看到了血迹 穿着盔甲就晕了过去
I saw the blood, and I passed out in my heavy armor.
我当时在山顶
I was on top of a hill,
所以我滚下去了
and so I started rolling down,
把坡上每一个人撞倒
knocking over everyone in my path.
绝对是开杂货店的料
-Definitely grocery-store material, right?
你想做什么就该去做 格雷戈
I think you should do whatever makes you happiest, Gregor.
抱歉 格雷戈 你先让一下 好吗？
I'm sorry, Gregor, will… will you excuse me?
好的 回头见 阿加莎
Sure. See you around, Agatha.
谢谢
-Thanks.
-你被袭击了吗？ -对
-Did you get attacked? -Yes.
被蝌蚪
By tadpoles.
在丑陋课
In ugly class.
我的美课不及格
Well, I failed beauty class.
你哪部分不及格？
What part did you fail?
微笑
Smiling.
微笑？
Smiling?
算了 我给你找了个可以吻的王子
Forget it. I found you a prince to kiss.
我已经找到了真爱 泰德罗斯
I already found my true love. Tedros.
我们第一次相见就心心相映
We had a connection from the moment we saw each other.
而且我们看起来很般配
Plus, we just make sense, aesthetically.
不幸的是 碧翠丝霸占了他
Well, unfortunately, Beatrix already has him.
你觉得她比我漂亮？
You think she's prettier than me?
我只是说 我们要找现在能亲的人
I'm just saying we need someone who's available now.
必须是真爱之吻
School Master said it had to be true love's kiss.
索菲 吻就是吻而已
Sophie, a kiss is a kiss.
是吗？
Oh, really?
你看 什么都没发生
See? Nothing happened.
必须是真爱
Has to be true love.
我可以玩玩的
I'm okay to keep this casual.
你可真可爱
Aren't you sweet?
把这个给他 告诉他我有多善良
Just give him this, and tell him how good and kind I am.
别怪怪的
And don't be weird.
你懂的 别说你的猫
You know what I mean. Don't talk about your cat.
-好吧 -好吧
-Fine. -Fine.
让他感兴趣就好 剩下的我来处理
Just get him interested. I'll handle the rest.
滚开！
Get off me!
你是谁？
-Who are you?
我是蓝森林的地精
I am the Gnome of the Blue Forest.
我以为地精都很矮
But I thought gnomes were supposed to be short.
我以为公主都很讨人喜欢
I thought princesses were supposed to be likable.
欢迎同学们 来这里集合
Welcome, students! Gather round.
我需要你们登记 让我知道谁活下来了 谁没有
I need you all to sign in so I know who survived and who hasn't.
喂 普通女孩
Hey. Normal girl.
读心术练得怎么样？
How's the mind reading coming along?
哦 抱歉 那…
Yeah. No. Sorry about that. That was…
我刚到的时候真的很不知所措
I was just really overwhelmed when I first got here.
是啊 这个地方会让人应付不来
-Yeah. This place can be overwhelming. -Mm.
但从没见过有这种态度的公主
Never had a princess cop an attitude like that before, though.
让人印象深刻
Really is quite impressive.
她们通常都对你微笑 冲你眨眼睛？
Mm, do they usually all smile and bat their eyes at you?
是啊 那太无聊了 所以谢谢你不无聊
Yes, they do, which is incredibly boring, so thank you for not being boring.
不 我其实很无聊
Uh, no, I'm actually, uh, pretty boring.
只有我的猫不这么认为
The only person who doesn't think so is my cat.
不 我…
Mm, no, I…
大家都说猫看人很准
Well, they say, uh, cats are good judges of character.
-是吗？ -是的
-They do? -They will.
我说过了
Now that I've said it.
我在这里很有名
I'm quite famous here, you know.
排名第一的童话王子
-Number one fairy-tale prince and all.
等你当上国王
Yeah, I think… I think when you become king,
他们得给你的膨胀的头
they're probably gonna have to find a bigger crown
找个更大的王冠
to fit on that swelled head of yours.
很好
Nice. Nice.
这是给你的
This is for you.
-嗯？ -不是我给你的
-Yeah? -Not from me.
我朋友索菲给你的
From my friend, Sophie.
一头秀发的女巫？
Oh, the… the witch with the gorgeous hair?
不 她不是女巫 她分错学校了
No, no. She's not a witch. She was just dropped in the wrong school.
不可能的 普通女孩 她肯定是在耍你
No, that does not happen, normal girl. She's definitely playing you.
这次真的分错了
Well, in this case, it did.
相信我 她绝对是个公主
Trust me. She is… definitely a princess.
对了 我叫阿加莎
My name is Agatha, by the way.
阿加莎
Agatha.
好多了
Much better.
你根本不普通
'Cause you're definitely not normal.
是好的那种
In a good way.
好 大家来集合
All right, come on, everybody! Come on, gather round.
我们来喝气球果汁吧
-Let's can the balloon juice.
我是尤霸 树林生存专家
I am Yuba, the school woods survival expert.
我在这里生活了几百年 一次都没死过
I've lived in them for hundreds of years, and I haven't died once.
至少
At least…
在我记忆中没有
…not that I can remember.
一点地精的幽默
Oh! That's just a little gnome humor.
好 我们该走了
So, off we jolly well go.
好了 把门打开
All right, let's get these doors open.
来吧
Go on.
打开
Open!
Open.
打开森林的门！
Open the forest doors!
谢谢
Thank you.
大家跟我来！
-Follow me, everybody!
要是没有森林生存技巧 任何冒险都无法进行
You cannot survive any adventure if you cannot survive the woods.
蓝森林为学生准备了各种会遇到的危险
The Blue Forest prepares students for any perils you may face.
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
格雷戈 你额头怎么了？
Gregor, what happened to your forehead?
我今天早上骑马又挂科了
I failed, uh, steed-riding this morning.
看来我不太擅长骑马
Turns out I'm not really any good with horses.
我可能需要戴眼镜
And I think I might need glasses.
杂货店更合适了
That grocery store's looking better and better, right?
离泰德罗斯远点 呆子
-Stay away from Tedros, you goon.
他是我的
-He's mine.
你好
Hey there.
来吧
Come on!
美丽的紫罗兰地
A field of pretty pansies,
但正如我们在童话故事里学到的
but as we know from our fairy tales,
美丽有时候是致命的
pretty can sometimes kill you.
不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no! No, no, no, no!
厚脸皮的植物
Cheeky plant.
婚礼上如果丢出这样的花束 还是不接为妙
That's, uh… That's one bouquet you wouldn't want to catch at a wedding.
地精幽默
Gnome humor.
好了
Right.
没事的 格雷戈
It's okay, Gregor.
碰不到你的 没事的
It can't get you. You're fine.
我真的很讨厌这个地方
I really hate this place.
快！来吧
Quick, quick! Come on.
这是尤霸最喜欢的部分
Ah, this is Yuba's favorite part.
南瓜地
The pumpkin patch.
白天很友善
Benign by day,
但到了晚上
but by night,
恐怖世界的死神会追杀你
a grisly horror world where reapers will hunt you down,
喝你的血
drink your blood,
卖掉你的手脚
and sell your limbs for spoils!
收割者 那是什么？
-Reapers? What are those?
其中的一个
One of those.
只是个稻草人
That's just a scarecrow.
三色紫罗兰也只是花
And I suppose pansies are just flowers.
记住 最厉害的邪恶会伪装成善良
Remember, only the best Evil can disguise as Good.
-我得走了 -千万不要
-I've gotta get out of here! -No, bad idea.
放我走！
Let go of me!
格雷戈 不要啊！
Gregor, stop!
你已经两次挂科了
You've already got two fails!
格雷戈！
Gregor! Gregor!
格雷戈 你不知道他们会对你做什么！
Gregor, you don't know what they'll do to you!
-回来！ -我会没事的！
-Come on, come back! -I'll be fine!
救救我！
Help me!
阿加莎！
Agatha!
格雷戈？
Gregor?
每个反派都有特殊的天赋 能练成强大的武器
Every villain has a special talent they can hone into a powerful weapon
打败宿敌
to defeat their nemesis.
什么是宿敌？
What's a nemesis?
你的终极敌人
Your archenemy.
除非你们其中一个被毁灭 不然故事不会结束
Your story will not end until one of you is destroyed.
好了
Now,
我要你们用独特的天赋让我目眩神迷
I want you to dazzle me with whatever you believe your unique talent to be.
霍特 你先来
Hort, you're first.
好 我在咒语课上练习过狼人
Well, I've been working on my werewolf powers in hex class.
看好了
Watch this.
好吧
All right.
下次我需要瘦削的只有一根毛的狼人
Next time I need a skinny, one-haired werewolf,
我会联系你的 坐下
-I'll make sure to call you. Sit down.
点点？请告诉我你可以做得更好
Dot? Please tell me you can do better.
看我的
Watch me.
有毒吗？
Is it poisoned?
有可能
It… could be.
总比一根杂毛好
Well, it's better than a stray hair.
这个可以改进
We can work with that.
索菲
Sophie.
真正的好人可以召唤森林里的动物
Those who are truly Good can summon the animals of the forest.
-我以前经常和我的松鼠朋友一起玩 -别说了
-I used to do it with my squirrel friends. -Oh God, give it up.
你怎么不召唤悬崖然后跳下去？
Why don't you summon a cliff and go jump off it?
你的母亲情结为什么总要盯着我来发泄呢？
Why don't you find someone else to have mommy issues with?
别说我妈
Don't you dare talk about my mother.
你对她一无所知！
You know nothing about her!
我知道她成功把你变成疯子
I know she did one hell of a good job turning you into a raving lunatic.
我讨厌你 你这怪胎
I despise you, you freak.
你所代表的一切
And everything you stand for.
更加证明我分错了学校
Which just proves that I am at the wrong school.
你想离开这里吗 公主？
-You want to get out of here, princess?
这疯子会很乐意
This raving lunatic's unique talent would be more than happy
永远摆脱你
to get rid of you permanently.
真愉快
This is delightful.
索菲 小心！
Sophie, watch out!
小心 读者 她越来越近了
Be careful, Reader, she's getting really close.
利用你的天赋
Use your talents.
我不知道是什么！
I don't know what they are!
你的松鼠朋友 索菲！ 让你的松鼠朋友来！
Your squirrel friends, Sophie! Call your squirrel friends!
救我！
Help! Help me! Help!
我猜松鼠也不喜欢你
Aw, guess the squirrels don't like you either.
可怜的小公主
You poor little princess.
让我结束你的痛苦
Let me put you out of your misery.
她会杀了她！
She's gonna kill her!
不！
No!
索菲 毕业前是不能杀人的
Sophie, you're not allowed to kill anyone until after graduation.
让它们停下
Call them off!
住手！
Stop!
我的天
Oh my God.
拉法尔
Rafal?
你做得很好
You're doing wonderfully…
索菲
…Sophie.
让开！
Move out of the way!
海丝特！
Hester!
你没事 没关系
-You're fine. It's okay. It's okay.
你会没事的 呼吸
Gonna be okay. Breathe.
你没事了
We'll make sure you're fine, okay? It's okay.
那是谁？拉法尔是谁？
Who is that? Who is Rafal?
别再提他的名字
Do not say his name again.
只能和我提
Not to anyone but me.
他是谁 他怎么知道我的？
Who is he, and how does he know me?
他是校长的弟弟
He's the School Master's brother.
他曾经是我们学校最有权势的人
He was once the most powerful being in our school.
他消失后 邪恶就没赢过善
Evil hasn't beaten Good ever since he disappeared.
但不知为何 你的能力吸引了他的注意
But somehow, your powers… your powers have drawn his attention.
我不知道我有能力 我不想要能力 我想…
I didn't know I had powers. I don't want powers. I want to go--
别抱怨了！
Oh, stop your whining!
你刚才在教室里做的事
What you just did in that classroom
证明了你的归属！
is proof to me that you are exactly where you belong!
我们是什么不重要
It's not what we are.
做什么才重要 索菲
It's what we do, Sophie.
走吧
Now go.
不要告诉任何人
And tell no one.
如果拉法尔再来找你 你要立刻告诉我
And if Rafal visits you again, you must tell me immediately.
去吧
Go, go.
如果她就是那个人 拉法尔
If she is the one, Rafal…
我会尽我所能把她送给你
I'll do everything in my power to deliver her to you.
我的爱人
My love.
不
-No, no, no.
我们当然不会恨
Of course we don't hate.
反派会恨
Evil hates.
正派会爱
Good loves.
反派攻击
Evil attacks.
正派防守
Good defends.
知念 正派何时能攻击？
Chinen, when is Good permitted to attack?
不能 正派只有防守的份
It isn't. Good can only defend.
如果正派先攻击就不是正派了
If Good were to attack first, by definition, it would be no longer Good.
没错
Precisely.
你们对他做了什么？
What did you people do to him?
什么？
I'm sorry?
格雷戈挂了三次科
Gregor failed three times,
然后他痛苦地尖叫着消失了
and then he disappeared, screaming in pain.
你们把他变成了什么？
What did you turn him into?
学校的规矩必须遵守
The rules at this school must be obeyed.
没有例外
There are no exceptions.
女士们 正如我说的
Ladies, as… as I was saying,
邪恶有很多武器
Evil has many weapons, but we…
但我们有动物
we have animals.
陆栖动物 水栖动物
Animals of the land, animals of the water.
女士们 今天我向你们介绍
-And so, ladies, today I present to you…
许愿鱼
…wish fish,
闪闪发光的水下的朋友
shimmering underwater friends,
能理解我们最深层的欲望
who understand us and our deepest desires.
是因为他们以前是这里的学生吗？
Is that because they used to be students here?
够了
Enough.
大家都有自己的烦恼
Not everyone earns their own story.
至少他们依然能成为别人幸福结局的一部分
At least they can still be part of someone else's happy ending.
女士们 如果你们的愿望够强烈
Ladies, if your wish is strong enough,
就可能会实现
then they might make it come true.
谁先来？
-Who's first?
我！
Me! Me, me!
希子
-Kiko.
是崔斯坦！他爱我
It's Tristan! He loves me.
让我试试
Let me try.
走开 希子
-Move, Kiko.
让开
Move. Get out of the way.
泰德罗斯
Tedros.
我们看起来很般配
We look perfect together.
永远舞会
The Evers Ball,
你们下周可能就会得到自己的初吻
where many of you may receive your first kiss next week!
阿加莎
Agatha.
该你了
Your turn.
有什么愿望吗？
Any wish?
你内心最想要的东西
Whatever your heart most desires.
我的愿望是回家 让我们所有人回家
I wish for home. For all of us.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
怎么回事？
What's happening?
够了 阿加莎 请停下
That's enough now, Agatha. Please stop.
我没法放手！
I… I can't let go!
退后！
-Get back! Get back! Get back!
我挂科一百年了
A hundred years since I failed.
100年来我一直在满足别人的愿望
A hundred years of granting wishes.
你是第一个许愿还我自由的人
You were the first to wish to free me,
第一个许愿让我回家的人
to wish me home.
谢谢
Thank you.
快跑！走！
Run. Run! Go, go, go!
快跑！
Run! Run!
阿加莎 走开！
Run! Run! Agatha, get out of there!
站起来！
Get up!
起来！
格雷戈？
Gregor?
嘿 格雷戈
Hey, Gregor.
-不要啊！退后！ -格雷戈！
-No, don't! Get back from it! -Gregor!
嘿 格雷戈 不知道我能不能帮你
Hey, Gregor, I don't know if I can help you or not.
但如果我可以 我会的
But if I can, I will.
我会保护你！
-I've got you!
别担心 阿加莎！
-Don't worry, Agatha!
你没事吧？
-You okay?
你做了什么？那是我的朋友！
What did you do? That was my friend!
它要杀了你！我救了你的命！
It was about to kill you! I've just saved your life!
你这个自以为是的家伙
You pompous ass, you killed him!
不是的！泰德罗斯救了你！
-No! -No! Tedros was rescuing you!
大家回宿舍去！
Everyone, back to your dorms!
今天的课都取消
Classes are canceled for the rest of the day.
你跟我来 走！
You, come with me. Go!
走！
-Go, go, go!
格雷戈 我好抱歉
Gregor, I'm so sorry.
-阿加莎… -别说了！
-Agatha-- -Stop!
这就是你所谓的善？
That's what you call Good?
毁了善良的人
Destroying someone kind
就因为他们无法满足你们不切实际的要求？
because they can't live up to your impossible expectations?
这到底有什么善的？
What exactly is good about that?
阿加莎 每个人都有自己的角色 你会明白的
Agatha, everyone has a role to play here. In time, you will understand.
我明白不了
No, I won't.
我说了 我不属于这里
I told you, I don't belong here.
你有什么毛病？
What is wrong with you?
很久以前 善是真实存在的
Once upon a time, Good was real and true.
现在我们处于以自我为中心的完美主义时代
Now we are in the age of self-centered perfectionism,
但你用你的愿望救了那个女孩
but you used your wish to save that poor girl.
你还记得我跟你说情感会带来魔法吗？
Do you remember when I told you that magic follows emotion?
最强大的情感是同情
The most powerful emotion is empathy.
你表现出的情感告诉我
The passion you've shown tells me that you,
你来对地方了
young lady, are exactly where you belong.
你是这所学校很久以来
You are the first real princess this school has seen
第一位真正意义上的公主
in a long, long time.
-我们得谈谈 -我们得谈谈
We have to talk.
你把我的信给泰德罗斯了？
Did you give Tedros my letter?
对 但这里发生了很糟糕的事
Yes, but something very bad is going on here.
就是说啊
Yeah, tell me about it.
我刚见到了一群蜜蜂
I just got visited by a swarm of bees
肯定是世上最邪恶的人
that is apparently the most Evil man in the world.
一个叫拉法尔的家伙
Some guy named Rafal.
那就是我看到的人
That's the guy I saw.
索菲 我们得离开 不管有没有吻
No, no, Sophie. We have to get out now, kiss or no kiss.
等等 泰德罗斯怎么说？
No, wait. What did Tedros say?
他说你朋友的右勾拳真不错
He said your friend had one hell of a right hook.
不是吧 你的眼睛怎么了？
Oh no. What happened to your eye?
问问你的朋友
Uh, ask your friend.
你打了他？
You hit him?
阿吉 为什么？
Aggie, why?
因为我居然敢救她
I just had the nerve to save her life, you know.
你完事之后到外面找我
Just meet me outside when you're finished doing whatever you have to do.
对不起
So sorry.
她脾气挺大 有时还有点暴力
She can be temperamental… and violent, apparently.
索菲 对吧？
Sophie, right?
对
Yeah.
你很会写信
You write nice letters.
我不知道还能怎么和你见面
I just didn't know how else to meet you.
他们把我们分开
They keep us so separate here.
对 最好把善恶分开 比较不乱
Yeah, probably best to keep Good and Evil apart. Less messy.
除非你倒霉到被分错学院
That is, unless you're unlucky enough to be trapped in the wrong school.
她没有上错学院
-She's not in the wrong school.
但她肯定不该和王子说话
But she's definitely not supposed to be talking to princes.
-不要啊！ -你没必要把她拽走 怎么回事？
-No! -No, you don't need to drag her--
泰德罗斯 我没做坏事！
Tedros, please! I didn't do anything!
嘿
Hey. Hey.
她是邪恶的 泰迪 让他们搞定她
She's Evil, Teddy. Let them take care of her.
你要带我去哪里？
Where are you taking me?
-末日房间 -什么？
-The Doom Room. -The what?
不！我没做坏事！
No! I didn't do anything that bad!
这就是你在这里的原因
Which is precisely why you're down here.
你
You. You, you, you.
拉法尔选择了你
Whom Rafal has chosen above all others.
你可能是我们学校一直在等待的救世主
You could be the savior our school's been waiting for.
但你却偏偏不要
But no.
你浪费时间在那个王子身上
You waste your time being distracted by foolish Everboy princes.
请不要伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
你有天赋异禀 索菲
-You've been given a great gift, Sophie.
我不会眼睁睁看你荒废
One I will not let you sabotage.
是时候
The time has come…
承认你站在哪一边了
for you to admit which side you're on.
拉法尔只想要真正邪恶的人
Rafal only wants one who's truly Evil.
显然 是你的美貌阻止了你
It's clear your beauty is keeping you and others
接受你的真实身份
-from accepting who you really are.
不要啊！
No! No!
喂 笨蛋 给我停下！
Hey, meathead. Stop!
天啊 我又做了什么？
Oh God, what did I do now?
你就站在那里 眼睁睁看着一只巨大的狗
Apparently, you stood there while one of the giant dogs
把尖叫的索菲拖走
dragged Sophie away screaming.
我救出公主 打败邪恶 我不会拯救恶人 好吧？
Hey, I rescue princesses and defeat Evil. I don't save it. Okay?
你知道谁是恶人？
You know who's Evil?
知道 那就是她学校的名字
Yes. Because it's literally on the name of her school.
我是好人 这是我应该做的 是我必须做的
Because I'm Good. That's what I'm supposed to do. That's what I have to do, okay?
-对这里要有点概念 -我很了解
-Start getting the concept of this place. -No, I get it fine.
这很荒谬
And it's ridiculous.
你知道你杀掉的那个恶魔骷髅吗？
You know that Evil stymph you killed?
对 那是格雷戈
Yeah, that was Gregor.
不是的 我能认出来
No, it wasn't. I would have known that.
但你没有认出来
but you didn't.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
问问多维 然后来告诉我你如何能辨认出邪恶
Ask Dovey. And then come back and tell me how you know Evil when you see it.
试着独立思考吧
You know what? Try thinking for yourself for a change,
你就可以超越学校让你看到的黑白分明
and you might see past the black and white this school wants you to see.
你会对自己的想法感到惊讶
You might be surprised by what you figure out.
这为何会发生在我身上？
Why is this happening to me?
因为这是你的命运
Because it is your destiny.
拉法尔？
Rafal?
你比你梦想中更厉害 索菲 毕竟…
You can be more than you ever dreamed you could be, Sophie. After all…
记住你有多特别
Always remember how special you are.
你总有一天会改变世界的
You're gonna change the world someday.
你很特别 索菲
And you are special, Sophie.
但他们都看不见
But they all refuse to see it.
你诚实 善良 有耐心 他们承认你善良吗？
You've been honest, kind, patient, and did they admit you were Good?
不
No.
你只能信任我
I'm the only one you can trust.
别管他们的规矩了
Forget about their rules.
想做什么就做什么
Do what you want, when you want.
如果他们不给你你想要的
And if they won't give you what's yours,
就去夺取
take it.
索菲被拉法尔的话说服
Drawn in by Rafal's words,
她决定要不惜一切代价
Sophie decided she would do whatever it took to win Tedros
赢得泰德罗斯的心 夺得真爱之吻
and gain true love's kiss.
丢了什么？
Lose something?
还是又想找人扇耳光？
Or just looking for another face to punch?
找不到索菲 我想确定她没事
Can't find Sophie. Just want to make sure she's okay.
她一定会来
Well, I'm sure she won't miss this.
今天是大日子
Big day today.
两所学校终于可以使用魔法了
Both schools finally getting access to their magic.
嘿 你应该知道 有些人说你是女巫
Hey, you should know some people are saying you're a witch.
-我以前听过 -好吧
-Yeah, I've heard that before. -Well…
我觉得你不是
For the record, I don't think you are.
是吗？
Yeah?
那我是什么？
Then what am I, hmm?
要是我知道就好了
I wish I knew.
因为你跟我以前见过的人都不一样
Because you're sure not like anybody I've ever met before.
我…不能这样做
I… I… can't do this.
不能什么？不能倒下？
Do what? Uh, fall down?
闭嘴！
Shut up!
各位 请坐好
Everyone, find your seats.
开始吧
-Let's begin. -Mm.
要获得魔力
To access one's magic,
必须释放手指魔力
one must first unlock one's finger glow.
一旦你掌握了手指魔力 那就是无价的
Once you've mastered your finger glow, it will prove to be invaluable.
我等不及了
I can't wait.
有些人有魔力后能变成动物
They say some people can transform into animals when they have their magic.
我想在晚上变成猫 睡在灶台地下
I want to turn into a cat at night so I can sleep under a stove.
太温暖了
Oh, it'd be so warm.
开始吧？
Shall we?
不要怕 永远 善人不会感受到痛苦
Have no fear, Evers. Good feels no pain.
无望…
Nevers…
一定会痛的
…it's going to hurt.
好
-Oh good. -Ugh.
排队！
Line up!
我先来！
Me first!
嘿！让我过去！
Hey! Let me through!
没门！让我先！
No way! Me first!
漂亮
Beautiful.
手指发光能让你意识到自己的力量
Your finger glow helps you become aware of the power inside you.
谢谢 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
你的手指发光时
When your finger glows,
意味着你感受到足够的情感 能让你施咒了
it means you've begun to tap into emotions powerful enough… …to cast a spell.
你的感情越强
The stronger your feelings…
魔法就越强
…the stronger your magic.
希望我没迟到
I hope I'm not late.
这是怎么回事？
What is this all about?
这个？原来你帮了我一个忙
This? Turns out you did me a favor.
我早就该改头换面了
I was long overdue for a makeover.
如果你不介意我激活我的能力
Now, if you wouldn't mind activating my powers,
我会非常感激
I'd be most grateful.
谢谢
Thank you.
♪ You should see me in a crown ♪
♪ I'm gonna run this nothing town ♪
♪ Watch me make 'em bow ♪
-♪ One by one by one ♪
♪ One by one by ♪
♪ You should see me in a crown ♪
-♪ Your silence is my favorite sound ♪
♪ Watch me make 'em bow
One by one by one ♪
-♪ One by one by… ♪
休战？
Truce?
谁想做脸部护理？
Now, who wants a facial?
拉弓！
Draw!
-♪ You should see me in a crown ♪
♪ You should see me ♪
-♪ Your silence is my favorite sound ♪
-♪ You should see me, see me ♪
♪ Watch me make 'em bow ♪
-♪ One by one by one ♪
♪ One by one by one ♪
不管是善还是恶 美容是全职工作
And whether Good or Evil, beauty is a full-time job.
亚瑟王传奇
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
关于什么？
-About?
我都控制好了
I have it under control.
我不这么认为
I don't think you do.
所以我要听一个曾经用痰做雕塑的姑娘的建议？
So I'm supposed to take romantic advice from a girl who used to make phlegm sculptures?
你为什么要这样？
Why are you acting like this?
因为我厌倦了当可悲的小索菲
Because I'm tired of being pathetic little Sophie.
那个用平底锅保护我的女孩不可悲
The girl who defended me with a frying pan wasn't pathetic.
我喜欢新的我
Well, I like the new me.
好 这本书怎么了？
Okay, what's with the book?
泰德罗斯的父亲因为美貌选择了新娘桂妮薇儿
Tedros's father chose his bride, Guinevere, for her beauty,
但她因为兰斯洛特背叛了他
but then she betrayed him with Lancelot.
亚瑟王失去了王位 伤心而死
King Arthur lost his throne and died of a broken heart.
这是约会该聊的事吗？
And this is supposed to be, what?
你不明白吗？
-Date conversation? -Don't you get it?
他父亲有这样的经历
After what happened to his father,
泰德罗斯不会因为美貌而爱上一个人
Tedros isn't going to fall for someone just because she's hot.
我们得向他证明你是好人
You need to prove to him that you're Good,
在所有人面前 没人能否认的那种
in front of everybody, in a way no one can deny.
好吧
Fine.
我该怎么做？
What do I have to do?
嗨
Hi.
抱歉 我不是故意让你分心的
Sorry. Didn't mean to distract you.
没什么能让我分心
Heh. Nothing distracts me.
也许我会带来好运
Then maybe I'm just good luck.
别高估自己
Don't flatter yourself.
这是王子的诀窍
It's prince's code.
只要你的心够纯洁 箭就会直飞
Your arrow flies straight if you're pure of heart.
你这是在做什么？
What do you think you're doing?
在我的家乡 男孩能做的女孩都能
Where I come from, girls are allowed to do anything boys do.
这和你是女生没关系
It's got nothing to do with you being a girl.
无望没法射箭
Nevers can't shoot.
缺乏纯洁的心
The whole lack of pure heart and all.
我说过 我不是无望
I told you, I am not a Never.
拜托 不是无望
Oh, please, not a Never.
手肘收紧
Keep your elbow tight.
伸展 放松握力
Extend this and relax the grip.
注意力在目标上会有用
It helps if you focus on the target.
加油
Take it away.
从来没有怀疑过你
Never doubted you for a minute.
你想一起玩吗？
Do you wanna hang out?
不知道 跟谁？
I don't know. With who?
和一个想更了解你的王子
Just some prince who wants to get to know you better.
该你了
You're up.
叛徒
Traitors.
我要吐了
I think I'm gonna be sick.
我不知道她看上他什么了
Ugh. I don't know what she sees in him.
这是对我们所有人的侮辱
It's an affront to us all.
不得不说 这是不对的
It's not right. I hate to say it.
太糟糕了
This is bad.
她是我的
She's mine.
我们的
Or ours.
她是无望！
She's a Never!
太恶心了
It's bloody disgusting.
我们该吃了他们
We should eat them.
他们一整天都在一起
They've been together all day.
太悲惨了
So tragic.
你知道 没人会料到我们会在一起
You do know that no one's ever wanting to see us together.
我知道
I do.
我和一个他们认为的无望在一起
And me being with someone who they think's a Never
会让学校陷入混乱
is gonna send the entire school into chaos.
没事的
I'd survive.
我要是带你去永远舞会 他们会疯掉
And they're all gonna lose their minds when I take you to the Evers Ball.
什么？
What?
-泰迪 你保证？ -当然了
-Teddy, you promise? -Of course.
什么？
What?
不
No.
你不会选择野蛮的狼人 而不选择我
You are not taking that underdressed she-wolf instead of me.
你们别愣着啊
One of you, do something.
要去哪里吗？
Going somewhere?
好狗不挡道！
Down your throat!
来啊！
Come on!
住手！
Stop!
Stop it!
我们为什么要放纵这种荒唐…
Why? Why are we still entertaining this preposterous--
拜托！
Please! Please! Please!
无望和永远之间的约会是违反规定的
Dating between Evers and Nevers is strictly against the rules.
-谢谢 -没错
-Thank you. -Yes!
善和恶不能在一起
Evil and Good do not belong together.
令人反感
It's rep… repulsive.
校长 容我说两句
Sir, if I may.
我要选择卡美洛的下一任女王 这个决定很重要
I'm responsible for choosing Camelot's next queen. I do not take that decision lightly.
索菲很好 她被分错了学校
I chose Sophie because she is Good. She's just in the wrong school.
如果他能相信 你们为什么不能？
If he believes it, why can't you?
再说 没什么能让真爱分开
Besides, nothing can keep true love apart.
这不是童话的第一规则吗？
Isn't that, like, the first rule of fairy tales?
如果是真爱
If it is true love,
这一定意义重大
such a thing would certainly be momentous.
在我看来 只有一个办法可以确定
It seems to me there's only one way to be sure.
故事的审判
A Trial by Tale!
-什么？不！ -先生！
-What? No! -But sir!
先生 我接受
Sir, I accept.
抱歉 故事的审判是什么意思？
Sorry. What is a Trial by Tale?
你们俩要从相反的方向进入蓝森林
Each of you have to enter the Blue Forest on opposite sides.
你们必须克服遇到的所有危险
You have to defeat whatever danger presents itself
在日出前找到彼此
and find each other by dawn.
绝对不能寻求帮助
Help, strictly forbidden.
索菲 我们可以的
Sophie, we can do this.
我们足够善良 足够强大 可以保护彼此
We're good enough and strong enough to protect each other.
-我们可以的 -什么？
-We can do this. -What?
他们这是自寻死路
This will get them both killed!
审判将在日落时
The trial shall begin…
开始
…at sundown.
卡梅洛的泰德罗斯
Tedros of Camelot.
加瓦尔登的索菲
Sophie of Gavaldon.
故事的审判不容小觑
A Trial by Tale is not to be taken lightly.
学校大门外有致命的危险
Mortal danger lurks beyond the school's gates.
你们愿意继续吗？
Do you still wish to proceed?
我愿意
I do.
是的
Yes.
当然
Definitely.
如果你们想放弃
If you wish to give up,
把红手帕扔到地上 就会被送到安全区
drop the red handkerchief on the ground, and you will be transported to safety.
审判开始
-Let the trial begin.
泰德罗斯！
Tedros?
嗨？
Hello?
我在这里！
I'm over here!
快来救我吧！
I'm ready to be saved!
花儿 真漂亮
Flowers. Pretty.
选择漂亮的吧
Let's stick to pretty.
嗨 我的小朋友
-Hello, my little friends.
我们都很美
We're all so beautiful.
是我
It's me.
救命！
Help!
不！
No!
泰德罗斯 救命！
Tedros, help!
泰德罗斯！
Tedros!
Tedros?
泰德罗斯 你在哪里？
Tedros, where are you?
好
Okay.
南瓜很有趣
Pumpkins are fun.
泰德罗斯 救命！
Tedros, help!
泰德罗斯！
Tedros!
索菲 快点！走！
Sophie, come on! Go, go, go!
索菲！
Sophie!
-索菲！ -好吧
-Sophie! -It's okay. Okay.
去找他 一旦他救了你 你亲了他 我们就能离开这个疯人院
Go to him. Once he saves you, kiss him, and then we can get out of this madhouse.
好吗？去吧
-Okay? Go.
-索菲！ -泰德罗斯！
-Sophie! -Tedros!
泰德罗斯 谢天谢地
Oh, Tedros, thank God.
不！
No!
索菲 拿起神剑
Sophie, grab Excalibur.
帮帮他
Help him.
索菲！ 把剑扔给我！
-Sophie! Toss my sword, now!
索菲 还愣着干嘛！
-Sophie, do something!
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
你作弊！
You! You cheated!
-你带来了阿加莎！ -不！
-You brought Agatha! -No!
不 我是自己来的 我发誓
No, I came on my own. I swear.
-对 -你明知道她不会帮我
-Yeah. -You knew she wouldn't help me.
-不是这样的 -这不公平
-That's not true. -That's not fair.
大家都知道该由王子救公主 而不是公主救王子
Everyone knows the prince saves the princess, not the other way around.
我就算死也无法改变世界
-I can't change the world if I'm dead.
我原本以为你是好人
And I thought you were Good.
不要！
No. No, no, no. No, no. No!
你
You.
是你干的
You did this.
我只是想帮忙！
I… I was just trying to help.
如果我不出手 你们早就死了…
Sophie, you know you'd both be dead right now if I hadn't.
骗子！你早知道会这样
Liar. You knew this would happen.
首先 你偷了我的学校 现在又想偷我的王子
First, you steal my school, and now you're trying to steal my prince.
你怎么能这么说？ 索菲 我是你最好的朋友
How can you say that? I… Sophie, I'm your best friend.
公主不能做女巫的朋友
A princess can't be friends with a witch.
你去哪里了？
Where have you been?
想和索菲沟通 但他们把她锁在房间里
Trying to talk to Sophie, but they locked her in her room.
对 他们把她关起来是因为她违反了规定 你们俩都有
Yes, they locked her in because she broke the rules. You both did.
你为什么要在审判中帮她？
Why? Why did you help her in the trial?
难道你不觉得她能自己做到吗？
Did you not think she could do it on her own?
我以为你相信索菲真的是好人
I thought that you believed that Sophie was truly Good.
我不相信
I don't.
我不相信任何人完全是善或是恶
I don't believe that anyone is truly Good or truly Evil,
因为人很复杂
because people are complicated,
尽管这里的人都在装
even if everybody in this place pretends they aren't.
小姐
Young lady.
-这所学校的规矩… -必须遵守
-The rules of this school must be-- -Must be obeyed.
你一直这么说
You keep saying that,
但如果真的恶降临 你却什么都不做
but what good are your rules if you don't do anything about it
你的规矩又有什么用？
when actual dangerous Evil is here?
拜托 索菲有很多问题 但我不觉得她危险
Please! Sophie is many, many things, but I would hardly call her dangerous.
不是索菲 是拉法尔！
Not Sophie. Rafal!
你说什么？
What did you just say?
拉法尔 我在森林里又见到他了
Rafal. I saw him again in the forest,
但你们什么都没做
but clearly, none of you have done anything about it.
又？什么意思？
"Again"? What does that mean?
你之前见过拉法尔？在这里？
Have you seen Rafal before? Here?
对 在血塔里 我跟校长说了
Yeah. In the tower of blood I told the School Master about.
索菲在教室里也看到了他
And Sophie saw him in her classroom.
莱索女士也是 她没告诉你吗？
So did Lady Lesso. Didn't she tell you?
莱索
Lesso.
我早该知道的
I should have known.
跟我来 我们会查个清楚
Come with me. We will get to the bottom of this.
来吧 去吧
Come on. Go!
索菲？
Sophie?
阿加莎让我给你这个
…Agatha asked me to give you this.
我…
I…
希望你快点好起来
I hope you feel better soon.
“亲爱的索菲 森林里发生的事 我很抱歉
Dear Sophie, I'm so sorry for what happened in the forest.
我从没想过要伤害你
I never meant to hurt you.
不管发生什么事
But whatever's going on,
都比你得到王子的吻重要
it's more than you getting a kiss from a prince.
我在树林里看到拉法尔了
I saw Rafal in the woods.
我觉得这里发生的事比大家意识到的更重大
I think what's happening here is bigger than anyone realizes.
这是真正的邪恶 我们必须团结一致
It's true Evil, and we have to stick together.
互相信任
-Only trust each other.
我们是最好的朋友
We're best friends.
你要知道 无论如何我都支持你
You must know, no matter what, I'm on your side.
我爱你 阿吉”
-All my love, Aggie.
别告诉我你真的信了
Don't tell me you actually believe that.
骗人的
It's a lie.
再说 那个王子根本配不上你
And besides, that prince wasn't good enough for you anyway.
你回来了？
You're back?
-但我以为… -我离开了你？永远不会
-But I thought-- -I'd left you? Never.
即使其他人都背叛了你
Even if everyone else has betrayed you.
-阿艾吉没有 -没有吗？
-Aggie hasn't. -No?
你自己看
-See for yourself.
我以为你相信索菲真的是好人
I thought you believed that Sophie was truly Good.
我不相信
I don't.
她一直在骗你 索菲
-She's been lying to you, Sophie.
从一开始就和你作对
Working against you from the very beginning.
她想把你拖回那个悲惨的小村庄
She means to drag you back to that miserable little village.
我会保护你
But I'll protect you.
我会帮你的
I'll help you.
别害怕
Don't be scared.
想象自己是即将变成蝴蝶的毛毛虫
Think of yourself as a caterpillar about to transform into a butterfly.
很快
Very soon,
你会变得比以前更美丽 更强大
you'll emerge more beautiful and more powerful than ever.
这所学校从未见识过的女王
A queen unlike this school has ever seen.
我可以给你他们梦寐以求的能力
I can give you abilities they only dream of.
你不只是最漂亮的
You'll not just be the fairest of them all,
你会是最强的
you'll be the strongest.
血魔法 索菲
Blood magic, Sophie.
我的爱
My love…
你愿意接受
…will you accept
这个礼物吗？
this gift?
我愿意
-I will.
你知道拉法尔在学校里 你没有告诉任何人？
You knew Rafal was here, in the school, and you told no one?
一定是我忘了
Ah, must have slipped my mind.
原来如此！ 忘了邪恶的灵魂吗 莱索？
I see! The soul of wickedness itself just slipped your mind, Lesso?
我是恶校院长 你不知道这意味着什么吗？
I'm the Dean of the School for Evil. Does that suggest anything to you?
这里的负责人都不知道这儿发生了什么
Yeah, it suggests that nobody in charge here knows what's going on in this stupid place.
-安静 读者 -不然呢 因为我皱眉头让我挂科？
-Quiet, Reader! -Or what? You'll fail me for frowning?
拉法尔想要索菲做什么？
Now, what does Rafal want with Sophie?
让邪恶胜利
For Evil to finally win!
就是这样
That's what.
你以为会发生这种事？ 拉法尔不会帮邪恶赢的
That's what you think will happen? Rafal won't help Evil win.
当他试图杀死校长 他自己的兄弟
When he tried to kill the School Master, his own brother,
他的目标是毁灭学校 两个学校
his goal was to destroy the school, both schools,
让他能掌控魔法
so that he can keep all the magic in the world to himself.
谢谢你 美容老师
Thank you so much, beauty teacher.
嘿 在你来这儿很久之前
Hey, I was the head of the Magical History Department
我就是魔法历史主任 红发
long before you got here, Red.
-是吗？ -对！
-You were? -Yes!
当时这里还没变得如此浅薄
Before this place became insufferably shallow
我还没被降级为美容术老师
and I was demoted to beautification.
我像为了微笑纠缠不放的人吗？
Do I look like I give a shit about smiling?
好 那我们得保护索菲
Okay, then we have to protect Sophie.
我们会尽快找到她的
-And we will, as soon as we find her.
索菲失踪了
Sophie is missing.
阿尼蒙说得对
-And Anemone is right. -Oh.
如果拉法尔和索菲联手 能毁了整个学校
Rafal will destroy this entire school if he joins forces with Sophie.
都是谎言
Lies. All lies!
这只不过是又一个让善赢的诡计
This is just another ploy to have Good win again.
相信我 不是的
Trust me, it's not.
如果我兄弟死而复生
If my brother is back from the dead,
我们可能都活不了 莱索女士
there is a good chance none of us will survive, Lady Lesso.
都活不了
None of us.
去找索菲 两所学校都找找
Go find Sophie now. Search both schools.
当然
Yes, of course.
阿加莎
And Agatha.
去永远舞会
Go to the Evers Ball.
索菲很可能在那里出现 如果她出现 带她来找我
Sophie may very well show there. If she does, bring her to me.
走吧
Now, go.
复仇
“有生命的娃娃”
"Living doll."
索菲
-Sophie?
Sophie.
你不是…我的天
You're not… Oh my God.
拉法尔对你做了什么？
What has Rafal done to you?
教会我接受真正的自己
Taught me to accept who I truly am, that's what.
这bu是你想要的吗？
Isn't that what you wanted?
我是美人 不是吗？
I am a thing of beauty, am I not?
拉法尔眼中的毒苹果
The poison apple to Rafal's eye.
才华远超其他所有人
The one whose talents soar above all others.
别告诉我你嫉妒了
Please don't tell me you're jealous.
加瓦尔登的利奥诺拉
Leonora of Gavaldon.
拉法尔告诉我的
Rafal told me.
利奥诺拉 渴望更多的孤独的读者
Leonora, the lonely Reader who wanted to be so much more.
他看到了你的内心 你没预料到的恶魔
He saw something in you. An Evil you didn't know you had.
所以他带你来这里养育它
-And so he brought you here to nurture it.
你很努力 但还是不够邪恶
You tried so hard, but you weren't Evil enough for him.
所以他背弃了你 尽管你爱他
So he turned his back on you, despite your love for him.
自此之后 你一直努力地向他证明自己
And you've been trying to prove yourself to him ever since…
希望赢得他的心
…hoping to win him over.
然后索菲来了
But then along comes Sophie.
他答应你什么了？
What has he promised you?
你答应过他什么？
And what have you promised him?
你们这么问真可爱
You're both such dolls to ask.
索菲…
-Sophie…
我的天
-My God.
我担心你没受到邀请就不会来
I was worried you wouldn't come without an invite.
然后我想：“阿加莎想做什么就做什么”
But then I thought, "You know Agatha. She does what she wants."
泰德罗斯 你看到索菲了吗？
Tedros, have you seen Sophie?
我们能谈点别的吗？ 比如森林里发生的事？
Look, for once, can we talk about something else? Like what happened in the forest?
-那是… -我找到她就可以
-That was-- -Yes, later. Once I've found her.
她对你大吼大叫
She yells at you,
不尊重你 把一切的错都怪到你头上
she disrespects you, she blames you for everything wrong in her life,
但你还是帮她
yet all you do is help her.
你为什么认为她值得你救？
Come on, why do you even think she deserves saving?
在加瓦尔登 我一辈子都被称为女巫
Look, back in Gavaldon, all my life, they've called me a witch.
他们当着我的面告诉我 我有多丑
They told me to my face how ugly I am
有朝一日 他们会烧死我和我妈妈
and how someday they'll get around to burning me and my mom.
整个村子都会大笑
And the whole village just laughs,
除了索菲
except for Sophie.
从我小时候起 她就是唯一支持我的人
She's the only one who has stood up for me from the time we were kids.
她就像我的姐妹
She's like my sister,
我不能放弃家人
and I'm not someone who gives up on family.
永远不会
Not ever.
你说得对
No, you're… you're right.
谁都不该放弃家人
No one should ever give up on family.
阿加莎 你把我从死神手中救了出来
Agatha, you saved me from that reaper,
让我超越黑白分明的视角看世界
and you made me want to see the world in more than just black and white.
从来没有人为我做过这种事
And no one has ever done anything like that for me before.
这让我意识到
And it made me realize
你是我的真爱
you are my true love.
-天呐 你的时机太糟糕了 -不 真的
-Oh my God, you've got the worst timing. -No, really.
我想清楚了 我爱你 阿加莎
I've thought it through, and I… I love you, Agatha.
泰德罗斯 别说了
Tedros, please, please stop.
拉法尔在利用索菲占领学校
Rafal is using Sophie to take down the schools.
等等 拉法尔是谁？
Uh, wait, who's Rafal?
索菲 你怎么了？
Sophie, what happened to you?
-我的天 -别担心 泰迪
-My God. -Don't worry, Teddy.
明天就会回来了
Should clear up by tomorrow.
不要放在心上 别毁了我们的夜晚
Try to look past it and not ruin our evening.
永远舞会！
The Evers Ball!
我来了
Here I am.
你说了要带我来的 记得吗？
You're taking me, remember?
-你答应过的 -索菲 求你了
-You promised. -Sophie, please.
安静 阿吉 主角们在说话
Quiet, Aggie. The protagonists are speaking.
我还是你的约会对象吧？
-I'm still your date, right?
你要信守承诺吗？
You going back on your promise?
因为如果好人违背诺言
Because… bad things happen…
就会有坏事发生
…when the Good break their promises.
没有承诺 你背叛了我 我和阿加莎在一起
There is no promise. You betrayed me. I'm here with Agatha.
-他没有和我在一起 -骗子
-No. Whoa, no. He's not. -Liar.
我感觉我掌握诀窍了
You know, I think I'm really getting the hang of this.
索菲 住手！
Sophie, stop.
不管发生什么事 我都可以帮你
-Whatever's happened, I can help you.
我是你的朋友
I'm your friend.
不 阿加莎
No, Agatha.
你是我的宿敌
You're my nemesis.
除非我们中的一个被消灭 故事就不会结束
Which means our story can't end until one of us is destroyed.
索菲
Sophie.
再见
Bye.
泰德罗斯
-Tedros.
快来
Come quick.
舞会取消了吗？
So, does this mean the ball is canceled?
我们必须阻止她
We have to stop her.
不 不要伤害苏菲
No, no, no. Nobody hurt Sophie.
瞧瞧她干的好事
Look at what she's done.
只能在她毁掉我们之前杀了她
Our only hope is to kill her before she destroys us all.
男人们拿起武器
Men, grab your weapons.
-是时候了 -住手！
-It's time to kill the witch! -Stop!
邪恶攻击 善良防守 记得吗？
Evil attacks, Good defends, remember?
你们不能攻击！
You can't attack!
首届无望舞会
亲爱的无望们！
My dear Nevers!
有客人来了
We have guests.
我们要怎么招呼他们？
-How should we greet them?
杀了他们！
We'll kill 'em!
放过他们吧！
Just leave them alone!
索菲 求你了 他们只是怕你要攻击
Sophie, please. They were just scared you were going to attack them.
我们为什么要这样做？
Now, why would we ever do that?
这也太邪恶了
That would be such an Evil thing to do.
让他们看看我们有多良善
Let's show them how Good we really are.
我们跳舞吧
-Let's dance.
向客人们问好
-Say hello to our guests.
这是派对礼物 小伙子们
Here's some party favors, boys.
拉弓！
Draw!
泰德罗斯 这是陷阱！
Tedros, it's a trick!
杀了女巫！
-Kill the witch!
开火！
Fire!
好吧
Well, now.
邪恶攻击 善良防守
If Evil attacks and Good defends,
现在看来
then it would appear
善良变成了邪恶
that Good has become Evil.
邪恶变成了善良
-And Evil has become Good.
太好了
Oh, so Good.
趴下 泰德罗斯！
Get out, Tedros!
泰迪 我们有好多要聊的
-Teddy, we have so much to talk about.
你和你的小军队试图杀害一群无辜的人
You and your little army just tried to kill a roomful of innocent people.
真是太邪恶了
Now that is quite Evil indeed.
看来有人一直在旁听丑化学
Looks like someone's been auditing Uglification.
不！
No!
求你了 索菲
Please, Sophie.
你必须阻止这一切！
You have to stop this!
太迟了
It's too late.
他们攻击了 现在我们来防守
They attacked. Now we defend!
-♪ There's no escape ♪
♪ I can't wait ♪
♪ I need a hit ♪
♪ Baby, give me it ♪
♪ You're dangerous ♪
♪ I'm lovin' it ♪
住手！
Stop!
♪ With a taste of your lips
I'm on a ride… ♪
想喝热巧克力吗？
Who wants hot chocolate?
-♪ I'm slipping under ♪
-♪ With a taste of a poison paradise ♪
-♪ I'm addicted to you ♪
♪ Don't you know that you're toxic… ♪
你觉得自己是王子吧 泰迪？
Call yourself a prince, Teddy?
不！
No!
-♪ Too high, can't come down ♪
♪ Losin' my head
Spinnin' round and round ♪
-♪ Do you feel me now? ♪
♪ With a taste of your lips
I'm on a ride ♪
♪ You're toxic ♪
-♪ With a taste of a poison paradise ♪
-♪ I'm addicted to you, don't you know… ♪
听好了 等等！
No, listen! Wait!
听我说！
Just listen to me!
♪ With a taste of your lips
I'm on a ride ♪
♪ You're toxic ♪
♪ With a taste of a poison paradise ♪
-♪ I'm addicted to you… ♪
来了 我的女王！
Coming, my queen!
不要啊！泰德罗斯！
No! Tedros!
感觉太棒了 我一整个学期都想这样
That felt wonderful. Been dying to do that all semester.
泰德罗斯！不要出事啊！
Tedros! Oh, Tedros! No!
退后 阿吉！
Back off, Aggie!
这是我的完美结局
This is my happy ending.
这就是你改变世界的方式？
So this is how you change the world?
这就是你一直想要的？
This is what you've always wanted?
把一切踩在脚底？
To simply have it all at your feet?
对 我犯的唯一的错是想换学校
Yup. The only mistake I made was thinking I needed to switch schools.
明明是学校需要交换
It was just the schools that needed to switch.
你犯的错是认为你需要这些
The mistake you made was thinking you needed any of this.
看看这把你变成了什么样！
Look what it's done to you!
看看他们把我们害得有多惨
Look at what it has done to us.
索菲 拉法尔是敌人
Sophie, Rafal is the enemy.
我们必须打败他
-We have to defeat him.
我宁愿打败我的宿敌
-I'd rather defeat my nemesis.
索菲 别！
Sophie, don't!
不要啊！
No! No! Oh my--
索菲！
Sophie!
现在只剩下最后一个仇人了
Now… just one last score to settle.
校长 你在哪里？
School Master. Where are you, old man?
是时候为你的错误付出代价了
Time to pay for your mistake!
为了复仇
Seeking revenge,
索菲在塔里寻找那个从一开始就辜负了她的人
Sophie searched the tower for the one person who had wronged her from the start.
至少她是这么认为的
Or so she believed.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思是你的故事才刚刚开始 加瓦尔登的索菲
It means your tale has just begun, Sophie of Gavaldon.
拉法尔
Rafal.
这都是考验 索菲
This was all a test, Sophie.
全部都是
All of it.
为了找到我的真爱而进行的考验
A test… to find my true love.
我不明白
I don't understand.
是我兑现了你的愿望
I was the one who answered your wish
把你带到了这里
and brought you here.
先知告诉我了你的潜力 我想帮你实现
The seers told me of your potential, and I wanted to help you fulfill it.
还有谁相信你
Who else has believed in you…
关心你
cared for you,
为你辩护
defended you,
给你一切？
given you everything?
当你使用那种力量
When you use that power,
看着敌人倒下
and watch your enemies fall,
感觉如何？
how does it feel?
我喜欢
I like it.
你从来不属于善
You were never meant for Good.
当然 我也不是
And of course, neither was I.
你为什么要假扮校长？
Why did you pose as the School Master?
他是我的兄弟
He was my brother.
几个世纪前
Centuries ago,
故事家被永久地授予我们
we were entrusted the Storian for eternity
因为我们的感情超越了争执
because our bond overrode our warring souls.
只要我们互相保护 就会永远年轻
As long as we protected each other, we would stay immortal… and young.
善与恶保持着完美的平衡
Good and Evil, in perfect balance.
但时间…
But time…
会让人不满足
time makes one discontent.
他怎么了？
What happened to him?
我们争吵…
We fought…
我杀了他
…and I killed him.
你杀了你兄弟？
You killed your brother?
你怎么能这么做？
How could you do that?
就像你想杀死你亲爱的王子一样
Well, the same way you tried to kill your beloved prince.
因为这是我们的本性
Because it's who we are.
我兄弟死后
After my brother's death,
我夺取了他的身份 隐藏我的意图
I assumed his identity to hide my true intent.
开始从内部破坏平衡
Started destroying the balance from within.
善恶学院没有错误
There are no mistakes in the School for Good and Evil.
但善赢了200年
But Good has won for 200 years.
现在赢了吗？
Oh, have they now?
通过一个个故事 我让他们腐败
Story by story, I have corrupted them.
用在烤箱里炙烤的老女人
Rewarding them for burning old ladies in ovens,
剪掉舌头的美人鱼
making mermaids cut out their tongues,
穿着烤红的铁鞋跳舞的女人奖励他们
forcing women to dance in red-hot iron shoes.
善良变得虚荣
Good became vain.
愚蠢
Foolish.
虚弱
Weak.
但你呢 索菲？
But you, Sophie?
你让我自愧不如
You put me to shame.
你在几周内让整个学校屈服
You brought the whole school to its knees in weeks.
超越善恶
Beyond Good and Evil,
你就是混乱
you… are chaos itself.
我们在一起势不可挡
-And together, we are unstoppable.
阿加莎！
Agatha!
泰德罗斯？
Tedros?
嘿
Hey.
你没事吧？
You all right?
我的天 我还以为你死了
Oh my God, I thought you were dead.
我没事 听我说
I'm fine. Listen to me.
我们必须一次结果无望
I need to put an end to the Nevers, once and for all.
不 泰德罗斯
No, no, no, Tedros.
学校之间的这场战争是错的
This whole war thing between the schools, it's all wrong.
如果我能联系到索菲…
-If I can get through to Sophie-- -After what she's done?
她做了这么多坏事 还回得了头吗？ 没意义 不可能的
No point. No way. It's not gonna work.
不 她被校长的弟弟利用了
No, no, no. She's being used by the School Master's brother.
他给了她血魔法 她无法承受
He's given her blood magic, and it's too much for her.
-她不知道自己在做什么 -她很清楚
-She doesn't know what she's doing. -No, she knows.
我能让她明白
I can reach her.
-我知道 -听我说
-I know it. -Listen to me.
-什么？ -她走了
-What? -She's gone.
她变成乌鸦去了校长的塔
She turned into a raven and went up to the School Master's tower.
-什么？ -战场在这里 阿加莎
-What? -The fight's down here, Agatha.
该放弃她了
It's time to let her go.
泰德罗斯
Tedros,
你之前告诉我 你会超越黑白地去看世界
you told me you were ready to see the world in more than just black and white.
这是你的机会
This is your chance.
我只需要你相信我
Please, I just need you to trust me.
跟我来救索菲 这样我们才能拯救整个学校
Come with me to save Sophie. That is how we'll save the school.
永远和无望
-Evers and Nevers.
-求你了 -泰德罗斯 救命！我们顶不住了
-Please. -Tedros, help! We can't hold them.
好 去找她
Okay. Go to her.
我会尽快赶过去 我答应你
I'll be there as soon as I can. I promise you.
索菲 你愿意和我一起吗？
-And will you join me, Sophie?
我们只需要真爱之吻
All we need is our true love's kiss,
邪恶之吻
Evil's kiss,
释放我们的爱
to unlock our love
把永远无望的门打开
and forever open the gates to Never After
你和我就能统治一切
for you and I… to rule.
我是你的王子
I am your prince.
我是你的真爱
I am your true love.
一直都是
I always have been.
你愿意和我一起吗？
Will you join me?
愿意
Yes. Yes.
于是邪恶终于赢得了真爱之吻
And so it was that Evil had finally won true love's kiss,
判处两所学校和校内的所有人
condemning both schools and all those within their walls,
不论善恶
Good and Evil alike,
皆要在痛苦中灭亡
to perish in agony,
让拉法尔的邪恶 真正的邪恶 控制世界
allowing Rafal's Evil… …true Evil, to overtake the world.
我做了什么？
What have I done?
为什么每个人都要死？ 我以为你想让邪恶赢
Why does anyone have to die? I thought you wanted Evil to win.
他们是我的朋友
Those are my friends.
他们只是童话世界的恶魔
They are merely fairy-tale Evil.
我们得扫清一切障碍 为真正的邪恶让路
We must wipe the slate clean to make way for true Evil.
欢迎来到永远无望 我的爱人
Welcome to Never After, my love.
不！我不想伤害他们 你不是说我们会统治他们吗
No! I didn't want to hurt them. I thought you said we'd just rule them.
我们会统治永远无望
And we will rule Never After,
所有学生 教授 能挑战我们的所有人 都死了
where every one of those students, every professor, anyone who could challenge us, is dead.
包括你的宿敌
Including… your nemesis.
■
这里埋着
阿加莎的尸体
不 阿吉！
No, Aggie!
这不是我想要的！
This is not what I wanted!
现在太晚了 索菲
Oh, it's too late for that now, Sophie.
你把所有人都赶走了
You've driven away everyone,
欺骗、背叛了所有人
lied to everyone, betrayed everyone.
你现在孤零零的
You're all alone now.
所以你是我的…
That's why you're mine.
放开她！
Get away from her!
阿吉！
Aggie!
你还活着？
You're alive?
对不起
I'm so sorry.
没关系 有我在
It's okay. I got you.
我对读者有更多的期待
You know, I expected more from a Reader.
你肯定知道阻碍真爱的人会有什么下场
Surely you know what happens to those who thwart love.
爱？这不是爱
Love? This isn't love.
你知道为什么善总是赢吗？
Do you know why Good always wins?
因为我们为彼此而战 关照彼此
Because we fight for each other, and we care for each other.
这就是善者的爱
That is what Good's love is.
恶人只为自己而战
Evil only fights for itself.
这与爱相差十万八千里
And that is the furthest thing from love on Earth.
这么漂亮的言辞
Such beautiful words
没有任何力量
that have no power or meaning anymore.
现在请你离开我的新娘
Now, if you'll please step away from my bride.
你永远不会拥有她 你这个怪物
You will never have her, you monster.
只要我还活着就不会
Not as long as I'm alive.
好吧 如你所愿
Well, as you wish.
不！别伤害阿吉！
-No! Not Aggie!
索菲！
Sophie!
索菲
Sophie?
不！
No. No!
不可能
It can't be.
决不能前功尽弃
Not after all this.
不！
No.
不
No. No, no, no.
你真以为那么容易吗？
Did you really think it would be that easy?
在我的学校？
-In my school?
在你父亲的手中 那把剑曾经征服过我
In your father's hands, that sword might once have vanquished me.
但在他无能的儿子手中
But in the hands of his ridiculous whelp of a son,
不过就是把大号黄油刀
it is merely an oversized butter knife.
你觉得这故事…
You think this tale…
写的是你的真爱
is about your true love.
不 写的是我的真爱
No, it's about mine.
邪恶之吻给了我力量
And the power Evil's kiss gave me
杀死善者未来的国王
to kill Good's future king.
我们可以阻止你
Or the tale of the girls who stopped you.
全剧终
The end.
我的天
Oh my God.
嘿 我的天
-Hey. Oh my God.
我的天 没关系
Oh my God. It's okay.
嘿 嗨
Hey. Hi.
我…
Aggie…
我为一切道歉
I'm so sorry for everything.
你没事 你没事了
Shh. You're fine. You're okay.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
我不想做邪恶的人
I don't wanna be Evil.
不 你不邪恶
No, you are not Evil.
人都会犯错
You're just human.
只要有你在就好
As long as I have you.
我们永远都是好姐妹
We will always have each other.
你保证？
You promise?
我保证
I promise.
好
Good.
我爱你 阿吉
I love you, Aggie.
你永远都是我最好的朋友
You'll always be… my best friend.
嘿
Hey. Hey.
不
No.
你不要死啊
No, please come back.
我也爱你
I love you too.
天啊
Oh God.
我的天
Oh my God.
嗨
Hi. Hi. Hi.
嘿
Hey.
对不起 我弄疼你了吗？
Oh, I'm sorry, am I hurting you?
我的天
Oh my God.
不要再这样了
Don't ever do that again.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
对
Yeah.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
我们的英雄打败了
And so it was that our heroes defeated
善恶学院有史以来经历的最大威胁
the greatest threat the School for Good and Evil had ever known.
童话世界没有灭亡
The world of fairy tales had not perished,
但永远改变了
but it had been changed forever.
善良和邪恶在一起？
-Good and Evil together?
一所学校？
One school?
现在怎么办？
Now what?
团结
Unity, perhaps.
也许还有友谊
Maybe… friendship, even.
好吧…
Well…
-不急 -不 细水长流
-Well, no rush. No rush. -No. Slow and steady wins the race.
你好
Hi there.
我的心是属于别人的
My heart belongs to another.
至于我们的两位英雄 终于能回到加瓦尔登了
As for our two heroes, there was finally a way back to Gavaldon,
阿加莎的吻让她们自由了
as Agatha's kiss had set them free.
有什么比朋友之间的爱更真实？
For what is truer than the love between friends?
还是我走吧
It's definitely best if I go.
阿吉 如果你想跟泰德罗斯待在这里 我明白的
Aggie, if you want to stay here with Tedros, I understand.
我会照顾你妈妈
I'll take care of your mom.
这是我的荣幸
It would be my honor.
谢谢你 索菲
Thank you, Sophie.
但我不能离开我的朋友
-But I can't leave my friend.
谢谢你愿意改变 泰德罗斯
Thank you, Tedros, for wanting to change.
总有一天我们会再见面
I hope we'll see each other again someday.
等等！
Wait! Wait!
♪ If I was an astronaut ♪
♪ I'd have a bird's-eye view ♪
♪ I'd circle 'round the world ♪
♪ And keep on comin' back to you ♪
♪ In my floating castle ♪
-♪ I'd rub shoulders with the stars ♪
♪ But I'm only human ♪
♪ And I'm drifting in the dark ♪
-♪ I'm up in space, man… ♪
两个女孩都受到了热情的欢迎
Both girls were met with open arms…
被家人接受
…and open minds.
她们从未觉得如此特别
They never felt so special.
♪ I've searched around the universe ♪
♪ Been down some black holes ♪
♪ There's nothing but space, man ♪
哦 不！
Oh no!
嘿！
Hey!
-♪ And I wanna go home… ♪
但一些事永远不会改变
Although some things never change.
-♪ Gravity keeps pullin' me down… ♪
-女巫！ -烧死女巫！
-Witch! Witch! -Burn! Witch!
除非你用你的力量来改变它们
That is, unless you use your power to begin to change them.
♪ I'm up in space, man… ♪
♪ Up in space, man ♪
♪ I've searched around the universe… ♪
这就是我们故事的结局
And that, you could say, is the end of our story.
但是泰德罗斯的箭刺穿了两个世界之间的传送门
However, as Tedros's arrow pierced the vortex between their worlds…
我需要你 阿加莎
I need you, Agatha.
显然 这只是一个开始
…it became clear that this was only… …the beginning.
♪ Gray sky ♪
♪ There's something bad in the balance ♪
♪ I'm staring into the darkness ♪
根据索曼·柴曼尼的著作改编
♪ And I like what I see ♪
♪ There's a thin line ♪
♪ Between a sinner and a savior ♪
♪ Never once did I ever ♪
♪ Think it would be me ♪
♪ Dead in the eyes, cold in the heart ♪
♪ A kiss or a cut, saw the scar ♪
♪ Don't you know that beauty can kill? ♪
♪ I'm caught in between ♪
♪ Two worlds apart ♪
♪ Devils and dreams ♪
♪ But do you know your heart? ♪
♪ Tell me, who do you think you are? ♪
♪ It's sick, and it's sweet ♪
♪ Went bad from the start ♪
♪ I'm caught in between ♪
♪ But do you know your heart? ♪
♪ Tell me, who do you think you are? ♪
♪ Blue light ♪
♪ Glowin' deep in the forest ♪
♪ I'm overcome with emotion ♪
♪ Pourin' out of me ♪
♪ Fake smile ♪
♪ I can cut like a dagger ♪
♪ A happily ever after ♪
♪ But who knows where it leads? ♪
♪ Attack to defend ♪
♪ Your body wins after all ♪
♪ What's a war between friends ♪
♪ When you're the one against me? ♪
-♪ I'm caught in between ♪
-♪ Caught in between ♪
-♪ Two worlds apart ♪
♪ Devils and dreams ♪
-♪ But do you know your heart? ♪
♪ Tell me, who do you think you are? ♪
♪ It's sick, and it's sweet ♪
-♪ Bad from the start ♪
-♪ Bad from the start ♪
♪ Devils and dreams ♪
-♪ But do you know your heart? ♪
-♪ You know your heart? ♪
♪ Who do you think you are? ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ Who do you think you ♪
♪ Who do you think you are? ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
-♪ Tell me, who do you think you are? ♪
♪ There's a wicked wind blowin' ♪
♪ I feel it in my bones ♪
♪ Everybody gonna know it ♪
♪ I'm about to hit the danger
Danger zone ♪
♪ Got me like, whoa ♪
♪ I can feel it now ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ Takin' over ♪
♪ I just touched down ♪
♪ Never gonna forget my name ♪
♪ Here comes trouble ♪
♪ Trouble, trouble ♪
♪ Here comes a no-good good time ♪
♪ Sign me up on the double ♪
♪ Whoa, yeah, here comes trouble ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ I'm gonna fire off a warnin' ♪
♪ Baby, three, two, one ♪
♪ By tomorrow mornin' ♪
♪ Ain't gonna be nothin'
But a trail of dust ♪
-♪ I'm like ♪
-♪ Whoa ♪
♪ Tried to tell you about ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ Can't nobody help you now ♪
♪ I just touched down ♪
♪ Never gonna forget my name ♪
♪ Here comes trouble ♪
♪ Trouble, trouble ♪
♪ Yeah, here comes trouble ♪
♪ Here comes a no-good good time ♪
♪ Sign me up on the double ♪
♪ Whoa, yeah, here comes trouble ♪
-♪ Whoa ♪
-♪ Trouble, trouble ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ Trouble ♪
♪ Whoo! ♪
-♪ Whoo! ♪
-♪ Trouble ♪
♪ Yeah, here comes trouble ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I see what's goin' on ♪
♪ I feel it coming strong ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ It's almost here ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah ♪
♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Get ready now ♪
♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
-♪ It's 'bout to go down ♪
-♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
-♪ Get ready now ♪
-♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Better get ready now
'Cause it's 'bout to go down ♪
-♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ah, ow! ♪
-♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Better get ready now
'Cause it's 'bout to go down ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Magic in the air ♪
♪ Feel it everywhere ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ It's gonna be so good ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah ♪
♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
-♪ Get ready now ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
-♪ It's 'bout to go down ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
-♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
-♪ Get ready now ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
-♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Better get ready now
'Cause it's 'bout to go down ♪
-♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Whoo, yeah, go down ♪
-♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Better get ready now
'Cause it's 'bout to go down ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
-♪ Get ready now ♪
-♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
-♪ It's 'bout to go down ♪
-♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
-♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
-♪ Get ready now ♪
-♪ Are you ready for it? ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
-♪ Better get ready now ♪
♪ 'Cause it's 'bout to go down ♪
-♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
-♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Better get ready now
'Cause it's 'bout to go down ♪
-♪ Oh, we of pure and beauteous hearts ♪
♪ Our goodness shall not wane ♪
♪ With grace and poise ♪
♪ Our weapon of choice ♪
♪ Our goals, we shall attain ♪
♪ To find true love ♪
♪ And win our prince ♪
♪ Bring honor to his name ♪
♪ The princesses of Good are we ♪
♪ So proudly ♪
♪ We proclaim ♪